Podcasting 2.0 for August
13th, 2021, episode 50.
It's max boost time.
Wait a minute, it's Friday the 13th.
That can only be good for a
project with Podcasting 2.0.
Hello, everybody.
It's time for the board meeting of
the next generation of podcasting.
Everything happening at
podcastindex.org, podcastindex.social.
I'm Adam Curry here in the heart of
Hill Country, Texas, and in Alabama,
the only man who knows every TLV number
by heart, my friend on the other end,
ladies and gentlemen, Mr.
Dave Jones.
7621629. See, I knew it. I think that's
it. That's the one. It's Boostergram week.
Oh, man.
It is indeed Boostergram week.
This is one of the most
fantastic inventions ever.
It is.
I feel guilty because we
created this thing because
I feel like we just created
it just to have fun.
It's actually very useful.
It really is.
It's just entertainment.
That's what it is.
I just like getting these messages.
I'm like, oh, what did this guy say?
And they're funny, too.
Well, it's a lot.
To me, personally, it goes
a lot deeper than that.
But before we even talk about
Boostergrams, I mean, Dave,
it is the 50th episode of Podcasting 2.0.
Can we have a couple of party hats?
Oh, yes. 50 big ones. Yeah.
What is this anniversary? Is
50 the diamond anniversary?
No, 50 is gold. You get gold.
What's the diamond? Is that 75?
Yeah.
Let me see.
Silver is 25.
Gold is 50.
I think five is paper.
And maybe 12 and a half is diamond.
Yeah, this is a paper.
Believe me.
There's a wood, too.
I've passed paper a couple times.
But today, 17 years ago, was the very
first episode of Daily Source Code.
Oh, really?
Yeah.
On this exact date, August 13th?
Yeah, I had to look it up on the wiki.
Nice.
If it says, if the Wikipedia
says so, then it must be true.
That never gets anything wrong.
Never, ever. Yeah, 2004.
It's appropriate.
Yeah, and so it was 2007, late 2007,
Dvorak and I started doing No Agenda.
We developed the value-for-value model.
Over time, it wasn't this
expansive the way it was.
And this is important as it
relates to Boostergrams.
The way it works in a perfect sense is
the same way we do it on Podcasting 2.0.
People send in support,
donations, value-for-value,
whatever it's worth to them, whether it's
the show, the project, one thing you said.
You cannot determine someone
else's value of information.
And they send that in, and that's
typically done through PayPal.
And then you close that loop by,
instead of a, you know, annoying,
incessant, intrusive commercial breaks,
you integrate the donations
with a short, short message.
And I say short, I emphasize that because
sometimes you have to remind people that
short is not 500 words.
That may be short for a newspaper column.
But that is the closing of the loop.
You tell everyone the
amount, the person's handle,
doesn't have to be a real name,
and then you read the note,
which turns out to be, in fact, content.
Because people typically
will send information or a
note about something they
heard in the podcast.
So that's the loop. That's the
whole value-for-value loop.
And it's consistent. It works
perfectly. You can build it over time.
You can have a well-run, well-financed
podcast based upon your audience.
But you don't need more than 1,000 people
if they really believe in your product and
they find it valuable.
Now, if you're looking to, you know,
to throw up something and do a podcast
and expecting to make money, okay,
well, there's places you can go for that.
But you might get eight bucks
at the end of the month.
So with the boostergrams, there's an added
thing in here that just blows my mind.
So now, you know, you're already doing
value-for-value with streaming payments,
and then you could do the boost.
And when the boostergram comes in,
so a boost is just, you know, boom,
I'm going to hit it.
I like something I heard.
But what I'm seeing is people are
sending a boostergram equal to a boost,
only you can add a message to it.
And it comes in for me. It comes
in with the person who sent it.
It comes in with the amount
of satoshis, comes in with a,
sometimes with at least a
time, so I know where it is,
where it has a link
that's even more perfect.
And so I can listen exactly what the
person was, why the person was boosting.
And the message almost always
relates to that part of the program.
So it's actually pushing people a little
further to create more content as they are
feeding back into the program
in the donation segment.
Does that make sense?
Mm-hmm. Oh, yeah.
Yeah, I mean, case in point, Podland
and Podnews, you know, this week,
both doing boostergram messages.
Yep.
And it brings, it makes you,
it's like a tieback to
a previous episode that
you don't have to do yourself as the host.
The listener does it for you.
Oh, Dave, it's better than that.
It's better than that.
Do you know how messy it is to be getting
payments from PayPal and notes through
email and matching those up?
I mean, Eric has been doing that for No
Agenda since, I think, almost the beginning.
And he's built a whole, well, we
have a kind of system amongst John,
myself, and Eric.
And Eric has actually built
systems to, you know,
to pull stuff in from
PayPal automatically.
But it's a mess.
And PayPal changes something, you know,
double-bite encoding rarely ever works.
So German names or anything with an umlaut
or anything like that always screws up.
And this is all self-contained.
I mean, it's obviously,
it's in a, it's in the,
it's on the blockchain or it's on the,
it's in the, um, uh, in the database, uh,
all the payments, the
way they come through.
So you can extract it.
It's, it's ready to go.
And the notes are right
where they should be.
It is a, it's a thing of beauty.
Here's what we need though.
The one piece that's missing is
going the, going back the other way.
Like, because what happens is somebody
will send a message, send a boostergram.
And I will, what I typically do when
somebody sends us a PayPal donation,
I get the email and I'll reply.
I've done the same thing.
Yeah.
I'll thank them.
I'll say, you know, whatever,
whatever, because it's appreciated.
It's meaningful.
I want to send little notes back.
Yes.
So what we need is the sender ID.
We need that sender ID field because
what we have now is we have,
we know the app and we know the, um,
the amount we know in it and the
amount, we know all that stuff.
We know where it came from.
We just don't know who it
came from and you don't
have to know who like real identities
in real life, but you, it
would be nice to know,
to be able to hit like reply essentially
and then send it back.
And because the sender ID would be like
just some unique hash inside the app,
like if it's coming from
pod friend, you know,
Martin's got a hash in there
that he can tie that back
to, so I reply and it goes
back to, back to pod friend.
And then Martin can route that or
Steven can route that directly to,
to the user in question
and they get a little feedback.
Now, is it possible to do that
with a payment alongside of that?
Can I send money back to somebody?
Well, you'd have to send at least one
Satoshi to get the message to go through.
So I'd love this.
This is so, this is, I mean, thank you.
You've just created a secure chat,
but don't tell anybody cause I don't
want anyone getting any ideas.
Um, yeah, you're right.
You're right.
That would be perfect.
Yeah.
I'd love to be able to bounce
that back to somebody.
Cause I was thinking
about that last night as
I was going through our booster grams and
I was like, man, I really
wish I could reply to this.
Now it's fun to wait for the show
and hear it on the show, but,
but like that little quick feedback.
Yeah.
I do that all the time
with PayPal messages.
Hey man, thanks.
Or whatever, you know, if something,
something pertains to it.
So here, so the interest, the thread that
interests me on podcast index.social,
did you hear I did like a, I did a
millennial girl there for a moment.
The thing that interests me,
I think I'm catching myself.
Tell me, tell me about that.
Let me tell you, let me tell you dive.
You've had, you've had
Starbucks this morning.
I'm drinking.
No, no Starbucks, please.
Drinking no agenda coffee.
No agenda coffee, son.
Hits you in the mouth.
When you have a flat
white, uh, mocha grande.
That's how you start talking.
Um, interesting thread.
And first I, well, I go through the whole
thread and I had different thoughts,
but I've come to yet a
different conclusion.
Um, no, I've never seen a
payment system like that.
It's certainly not
implemented on podcasts.
Let's just take a Patreon or, um, uh,
PayPal is maybe a better example.
I've never seen a system where there
was ever a feature or as far as I know,
a request to not send a message
to someone that someone does
in a donation if it's
under a certain amount,
which is the thread I'm
referring to is the, oh,
I don't want to be spanned by evil people.
It'll hurt my feelings.
So I want to be able to
have a level that people,
which is very interesting
because it is, in
fact, the antithesis of value for
value was my initial thinking.
So let me just make sure you know
what I'm talking about here, which.
Yeah.
You're talking about abuse, abuse message.
And so what I, what I saw coming
through was, okay, we can do, we,
you should be able to block,
you can block by sender ID.
If we have that implemented, then
there's still this like, well,
it has to be at least X amount.
And I, and at first I thought,
you know, it's such the,
it is truly the antithesis of value
for value, but it really is because you're
setting a minimum value that you expect.
And so if you say, this is
what I believe will happen.
Uh, if you say, well,
you have to send at least a thousand
Satoshis in order for there
to be a message attached because
that's abuse, my abuse mechanism.
And you know, let's just take a
thousand as a, as a baseline.
It doesn't really matter what it is.
I believe most people will
then send you a thousand
Satoshis just from my 14 years of
experience that they will not say, Oh,
let me do three, three, three, three,
or let me do 5,000 or 10,000.
I believe that that limits the sender
to, uh, that number that they see.
And it may even be pre-filled out.
Um, so that's just something to consider.
But then I also thought, wow,
that's kind of cool because I
wasn't Satoshi is not going
to stop me if I want to send
something horrible to somebody.
I'm going to do that over and over again.
So what are you going to set it at?
10,000?
So it just seems like I, the, the
blocking by sender of someone, you know,
like you don't want to see some offensive
stuff that you know, someone's doing that.
I'm all in.
I just think the setting a Satoshi
limit is crippling down the road.
Just my personal feeling.
Okay.
So here's, here's my, here's
my feedback to your feedback.
The limit on how not on like, at what
level it becomes, um, there goes my dog.
Hang on a second.
Let me ring it.
It's okay.
I'll just sit here.
Oh, you know what?
I'll open up the door for everybody.
I'm sorry.
They're still out there sitting there.
I can see their faces
in front of the window.
Come on in.
Come on in, everybody.
Sit down.
I'm sorry.
Yeah.
The board meeting has already started.
We kind of jumped the gun.
Uh, we've got the crappy
Starbucks over there.
Premium.
Yes.
That's the no agenda coffee.
And then we have the real
premium stuff over there.
Don't ask where that came from.
Everyone's here, Dave.
I let them all into the boardroom.
I'd let them all in.
Matt is Max here.
No, he's not here.
I let everyone else in the boardroom.
Oh, no, no.
He's our surprise guest.
Thanks for the spoiler.
Oh, sorry.
I mean, uh, it's Max, uh, Smith.
Yeah.
That's who it is.
Max Smith.
All right.
You were going to tell me
about the, uh, uh, the,
the feedback to your
feedback to your feedback.
Um, so, oh, there's two,
there's two like levels here.
So there's the level at which somebody
can send, can send you through the app.
And that's currently like with
CurioCaster, it's a thousand sats.
So I think that, that is,
seems like to me more a function
of just routing and trying to
make sure that app can justify
a mess, you know, a message.
So it's like, okay, I'm going to set this.
Ah, yes.
Okay.
I, yes, I totally agree.
Yeah, I agree.
And then, but then there's the
silent discarding on your own side.
So then you can say on your side,
I'm, I'm just not even going to like,
I'm going to set this limit on
here and I'm not even going to see
anything that comes in
unless it's above a certain.
Ah, so that's on the receiver side.
Yeah.
So then you're limiting it, but you're
not, you're not pushing that limit.
Well, and I'll just say one other thing
from my experience when I, so every day,
uh, every show day I get, uh, we'd get a
spreadsheet from Eric that, uh, you know,
like a really good day.
It could have 300 entries there.
I mean, it's, it's, you know.
You're talking about on no agenda.
Yeah.
No agenda.
And the first thing I
do is I scroll all the
way to the bottom and I look at everybody
in the ones, the twos, the 11s, because
they also send messages, which, you know,
we have a cutoff on no agenda, $50 or
above we read and underneath we don't.
A lot of those are ongoing subscriptions,
but a lot of people just send, you know,
a couple bucks, five bucks.
And I always look at those
and there's sometimes
there's real gems in there
that I like to pull out.
So, you know, just, just for
everybody, you know, if,
if once something like this gets
implemented, make sure you
take a look at the bottom too.
And that's where some,
some beauties lie for programming
purposes and for community purposes.
And the set, if, if we can
get the sender ID in there,
that's another way in which this can work.
Because if you identify somebody who's
just being a real dick, you can, you,
you could limit them.
You could discard stuff from that
person based on their sender ID.
And that's not something
that the sender can
control if they're going through an app.
Now, if somebody wants to go and set up
a, you know, a lightning node and do,
I mean, I mean, at that point, I mean, God
almighty, I mean, they could send you a,
you know, they could send you a
glitter bomb in the mail too.
So, I mean, I like.
So I'm, I'm hopeful that the thread ends
now because it's just so distracting to me.
It's like, okay, okay.
It's great.
I don't like, it's
great, but let's get it,
let's get it working and
then we'll make it great.
It's great.
But is the story of podcasting.
That's the subtitle of podcasting.
It's great.
But so, so the other thing that, man,
I got such a boost of energy this
morning hearing Martin on Podland.
Oh yeah.
Martin, he's all over the place.
And that, you know, he's been, he's
been out for a couple of weeks.
He's been moving.
He's been on vacation and he just
came back and he just came in.
Ah, come on.
I fuck up things all the time.
So Sam had a small mistake.
I heard it too, though.
I'm like, oops.
I'm just ribbing him.
I like that.
And, um, yeah, Martin was, it
was just really like fresh air.
It's like, yeah, you know,
we've got the cross,
cross app comments and working on that.
And he's got all kinds of ideas and he was
talking about pod ping and it was good.
I mean, it was just nice to have him,
uh, have him back on the wagon here.
You know, what was nice about it is the,
is so many of these podcast interviews,
interviews that you hear, um, they're
business, they're business guys.
And then maybe they're taking
VC and all this kind of stuff.
And they come, they come on to the pot,
the different shows and they just have,
they have their line that they've got.
This is their pitch.
I mean, it's their marketing pitch.
And so it's nice to, you know,
Martin shows up and it's just like,
yeah, I made this thing.
I just do this stuff.
Yeah.
You can tell in the way
that he talks that there's
really just absolutely no agenda backing
what he's saying at all other
than just, Hey, this is cool.
I like being on the show, you know?
Yeah.
It's great.
It's really refreshing.
But he's also really always open.
Like, yeah, I hope to be the number
one app and make billions of dollars.
But right now I'm having a really
good time making this app,
which I think is for everybody
kind of similar, similar feeling.
But it was really good.
It was nice to, I'd haven't
finished the whole pod.
I finished his interview part.
I haven't finished the rest of pod land.
That whole episode was really good.
I was quite pleased with it,
especially the Boostergrams.
Yeah.
It just adds a whole new dynamic to the
show because you, you as the listener,
I don't go back into Boostergrams again.
Well, no, but before you even do
that, I mean, let's just make sure.
Here's your cue to boost.
You know you want to.
Boost.
It works, people.
It works.
I see the time codes.
I see the chart.
Yeah, I do.
I see the stats, but like it's,
it ties the listener into the
show through other listeners.
So I just enjoyed hearing other people
say things and you just, I don't know,
you just felt like a participant.
Yes.
This is what I've been saying to
other podcasters for 14 years.
This is why it works.
It works because A, people like
to hear themselves on the show.
It's just, I mean, I'm a radio
guy, so I know these things.
This is not science.
This is history.
And it completely contributes to the show.
You know, of course you'll get
things like, hey, love the show,
but you'll get people saying,
I mean, we see it ourselves.
We'll go through them today.
You want to do them right
now just to jump ahead?
Do you have it separated like
that or is that not possible?
What, the Boostergrams?
Yeah, just run through
a couple Boostergrams
right now and just read
them out and you'll
see exactly what I mean.
I got a whole stack of Boostergrams.
I know.
We got boosted up the wazoo.
It was quite interesting.
Do you want me to pull like, we could do
this, I could pull a couple of random ones.
Yeah, pull some randos.
I'll pull a rando here.
Let's talk about pull two.
I'm going to pull two.
Here we go.
There's one that says a thousand.
A few of these are make
goods from last week
because I was on the road
and I couldn't decode them.
Oh, okay.
Aaron at Solonomics, a thousand sats.
He says, when I said violent ending, I
meant it cut the end of the, off the outro.
Turns out it was just a bug on
my retarded Android handset.
Right.
So this is, this is, he sent a, I
think a previous Boostergram, which,
which said, hey, why does
the show always end so violently?
Yeah.
And we didn't know what the
heck he's talking about.
The shame, let's see.
The shame I felt when I
realized I had meant to
send you another thousand sats
for wasting everybody's time.
Never ask permission.
Only ask forgiveness.
Back to work.
See, this is, this is
exactly how they work.
And bonus, you get paid twice
telling you this is, you know,
so just speaking of value for
value, speak up yesterday on no
agenda, something outrageous happened.
I never listened to no agenda, um,
Thursday show because I do
not want to be tainted.
Good.
We got an Insta Duchess
donation of $10,000.
Holy crap.
My words.
Exactly.
Jeez.
That's never happened.
We've had big numbers before.
Um, but, uh, and with no agenda, we
have different levels and, you know,
uh, a night is a thousand dollars.
And it really, it really was just a
gamified thing that everybody liked.
And then we added the rings
and people like that.
Um, and yeah.
God almighty.
10 grand.
And you know what I didn't
hear after we did our show?
I didn't hear anyone or see any
emails from anybody saying, well,
I don't have to support you now, do I?
Yeah.
And that's, that, believe me,
that fear, I've had that fear.
I had it for many, many,
many years until I figured out
that it's just not how it works.
Just not how it works.
And, and I wish I could put this into
science somehow, you know, in fact,
I predict quite the opposite.
I think other people for a little bit,
maybe might step up with
some bigger donations and
yes, people will drop off.
And the thing is, it always evens out.
It evens out.
We've grown, I think year over
year, you know, five to 10%,
maybe a little bit more, uh,
in the, in the, during the,
during the Rona, but in general,
it's just been a very like Bitcoin.
This is very, you know, if you, if
you, uh, if you even it all out,
you smooth out the curve.
It's just a slow, slow, slow build.
And, um, you know, it just evens out.
I wish I could explain it.
I wish I could.
It's hard to say you, you get
exactly what you deserve.
It's, uh, it's, and we'll talk, we
can talk about this with our guests,
but it is the, in my opinion, this
would be tied into human action.
This is, this is because economy,
economics at its core, uh,
and this is why I'm an Austrian
economics at its core is not a, is
not a math, is not a math problem.
Economics is not mathematics.
Uh, economics is the
study of human action.
It's praxeology.
So.
I'm sorry, did you say praxeology?
Yeah.
Praxeology.
What's praxeology?
The study, study of human
behavior, human action.
Oh.
And economics is not a, you know,
it's, it's not a math class.
It's, it's a study in how people behave.
It's why people do things.
Yes.
True.
Of course.
And you know, that.
That's, we get time preference
and that kind of stuff.
Yeah.
You can't, you can't understand economics
without a fundamental understanding of,
of what prompts people to do things.
And, uh, that's, this is one of the, one of
the things, one of the mysteries of, um,
marginal utility is, well,
you think that somebody,
you see somebody else do something
and it makes you want to do that thing, even
if it doesn't necessarily make sense to
the person that's being done to.
Well, I think you're correct.
We, we cannot discuss this topic
without bringing in our guests.
I think, I think, yes, from, from
Prague, ladies and gentlemen.
Now this is, uh, I, I call
him, uh, the OG, an OG,
even though he hasn't been in Bitcoin
that probably, uh, even not as long
as I have, but he's definitely,
as far as I know, a maximalist.
Uh, he's the developer of
Wasabi wallet, wallet.
He's, uh, a free software
entrepreneur, self-described.
Uh, he's been hanging around,
no agenda social, very,
very cool to have him there and very nice
to have him on the show.
Ladies and gentlemen, here at the
board meeting, Max Hillebrand.
There we go.
Hey Max, now is it, should
I be saying Max Hillebrand
or Max Hillebrand or how do you prefer?
Max Hillebrand.
Oh, okay.
But Max will do.
Max.
Guys, you know, when,
when hearing your voices,
I simply cannot resist the
temptation to toss you some sats.
Oh, did you boost?
Unfortunately, you know,
like clean feet does not yet have
a Bitcoin wallet integration.
So I got my breeze wallet open, you know,
listening to podcast episode 49 again
on mute and smashing the boost.
So if you guys see some
weird boosts at weird
timeframes from the last
episode, please me.
Yeah, you're buddies with
Roy, you need to get,
you need to get in Roy's
ear about booster grams.
We need, we need to get
him, him messaging here.
You know, I've, I've been
having that thought in
mind for like a week or
so to open a feature
request on GitHub and I was too lazy to
get it done and always postponing it.
But no, no, I, I.
This is why you fit well
within our community, Max.
We're all like, I was
too lazy to get it done.
I'll do it tomorrow.
Oh, whatever.
Yeah.
That, that brings up another,
that brings up my first.
Well, can I get a little background on?
On Max first, because I don't
know if everyone knows about him.
Max, give us some of your background.
What a lead in.
Amazing.
That shows the years of
experience in podcast.
Yes.
Thank you.
Thank you for pointing that out.
Yes.
I'm very proud of my skills.
My time.
There are research here on the podcast.
But without kidding, my background is
in economics and entrepreneurship.
That was always super fascinating to me.
And, you know, I was always
hustling at an early age,
trying to earn some more money by
being useful, basically.
And then I discovered Austrian
economics as a science
that really explains how entrepreneurs
can be more productive and
why it's actually such
a meaningful task to be an entrepreneur
and why this is so useful, not just
for yourself, but for society.
And this was very much in
contrast to the Keynesian
bullshit that they teach you in school.
So I was very much happy
that I got to know Mises.org
and this devoured all these books out
there because that really
helped me to understand.
Is that where you found Tom
Woods, I'm sure, through that?
Tom Woods, yes.
But, you know, actually, the guy that
really turned me on was Murray Rothbard.
I remember reading his book, For a New
Liberty, you know, a small pamphlet,
maybe 100 pages
or so, explaining in very easy
language with logical rigor, you know,
why freedom is the only reasonable option.
And I remember reading that book
twice in one night, you know,
skipping the next day university
lecture because I just
need to finish that second
reread because I was just enthralled.
It explained exactly what I
intuitively understood to be true.
And it provided a irrefutable logical
proof that it, in fact, was true.
And that's pretty amazing to realize.
Now, I like Rothbard.
I would say if anybody wants
to look up Rothbard and start,
I don't know about how you feel,
but I would feel like maybe man economy
and state would be a good place to start.
And that might be a little
bit a little bit easier
to come into like sideways
into the economics.
Yeah, you know, man economy and state
is like this behemoth, you know,
like 1,800 pages or something.
And like, you know, every
paragraph is important.
I feel that Atlas Shrugged by Ayn
Rand is a good way to get into it.
It's more than 1,000 pages.
Well, like definitely the way not to get
into Austrian economics is through Human
Action by Ludwig von Mises
because that book is inscrutable.
Like it's very, very
difficult to get through.
Now, did you grow up in Prague, Max?
No, actually, I'm in
Germany and was also always
in the Alp region in
Switzerland and Austria.
So, therefore, close at home in
the Austrian school of economics.
Sure, sure.
But so then how I got into podcasting more
specifically was that when starting to
dive down in the Bitcoin rabbit hole,
you know, you listen to a lot
of podcasts and videos, right,
to try to understand this.
And there was this channel,
the World Crypto Network,
basically a podcasting network.
And they had an amazing amount of teachers
kind of starting out to produce there.
You know, guys like Andreas Antonopoulos
uploaded their first video there and you
might have heard of him.
Yeah.
And so this guy, Matt Bitcoins,
was doing a call-in show to the earlier
topic, right, of guests actually calling in.
And I remember that I
was thinking like, man,
I've heard a couple of
times on the show that like
the economic aspects
weren't really explained.
And I know that how to explain it
nice so that people might get it.
So how about I just call in,
you know, and start talking?
And then, you know, super, how do
you call it, anxious and excited.
I jumped into that call and gave a quick
rant about why Austrian economics is so
beautiful and why it's cool for Bitcoin.
And ultimately, I stuck around and just
continued to calling in because, well,
I'd like to hear my own voice on the show.
Yeah, sure. That's how we
all start, Max. Trust me.
Exactly.
And for the chicks.
Yes, for sure.
Huh. Okay.
Well, and so when did you
bump into podcastindex.org
and the Mastodon and Podcasting 2.0?
You know, it's somewhat
similar to with Bitcoin.
You know, the first
time you hear about it,
you usually kind of just
ignore it, you know.
And the same, I think, happened
to me with Podcasting 2.0.
Like, I heard about it as like pretty much
as soon as you announced it, I remember.
And I was like, oh, cool.
You know, podcasts, lightning,
that's awesome, man.
That sounds cool.
And then I forgot about it.
Even though I'm like, you
know, complete overlap.
And then I saw on your website that,
and it was half a year ago or so,
that you had the Sphinx donation app.
And, you know, I'm like,
I'm so deep in the rabbit hole that
I know these cutting edge projects,
you know, and I know the
people that work on it.
And I'm like, the fuck?
Like, Sphinx has like 50 users.
Why is this huge podcasting company
putting this stuff on their website?
They pioneered it with us, man.
They were dynamite.
I miss those guys.
They're busy with something else, I think.
But I miss them kind of in the community.
Me too.
Yeah.
Lots of stuff to build.
Hey, it still kind of works.
You know, we know pretty much
what's coming from Sphinx,
and it's still cranking away.
So, that's good news.
So, yeah.
You know, the good thing about Sphinx,
just to follow up with that real quick,
I was thinking about this the other day,
because they have sort of gone ghost.
But the cool thing about it is
they built it in such a way,
they built it to be decentralized
from the very beginning.
Yes, exactly.
So, everybody runs their own nodes.
So, like, people that have Raspi Blitz
running Sphinx, they're not affected.
Even if Sphinx wraps up, you know,
closes up shop and just disappears.
They can still participate.
Yeah.
Which is cool.
I mean, that was the right way to do it.
Yeah.
Yeah, totally.
It's a tough onboarding experience,
but it's, yeah, I agree.
I still look at it every single day.
You know, I got some issues with routing
and stuff for some messages and things.
Yeah, but, I mean, it's amazing that
half the shit works anyway, in my mind.
It's like, wow, look what
we're doing with a SAT.
We're somehow sending
that around this network.
That's exactly it.
And, you know, I remember Lightning
Network in late 2017 and trying to use it.
I mean, you have no idea about how easy
onboarding is nowadays compared to that.
Well, but this is what I always say, Max.
It's the same with podcasting 1.0.
We used to have to say on our
shows, okay, now go to my webpage,
look for the orange RSS
little icons, a little bitty thing.
Now, right click on that.
Yeah, that's the right
hand click on the mouse.
Do copy link.
Now, you want to alt-tab back to
your podcast, your podcatcher.
You want to hit this ad.
You know, so we went
through all that stuff.
And that really didn't even get,
quote-unquote, fixed until Apple came along.
But then it wasn't even important.
After a couple of years, that went
away and everything innovated.
And the apps themselves were
how people got their podcasts.
And so I've seen this development.
But it does take a while.
It just takes a while
for people to catch on.
Yeah, you know, and the closer you
look to the nuances of those problems,
the more you
realize how much work needs to be done
and how of a long game this actually is.
But it's a race, in my experience,
it's a race towards human learning.
And you usually meet
somewhere in the middle.
It's like humans start, quickly figure
out, oh, I got to do this, this.
I don't know if you have kids,
but I've watched my daughter do
this for, you know, 30 years.
She's like, oh, no, I just do this.
Like, what did you just do?
How did you do that?
I said, no, that's how you do it.
And I'm like, wow, that could be
done easier with one fucking button.
But, you know, so those two pieces often
come together, I think, in development.
And that's really what happened
with the Freedom Controller.
Now I know what it is.
You know, we just, we don't, go ahead.
I'm not concerned about
people being able to
ultimately do things that they want to do.
When I look around at the number
of people who pull up their tasks,
their task switcher on
their mobile phone and spend 10 minutes
flicking up to get rid of all the apps,
to close all the apps.
I'm like, oh, well, clearly,
if you want to do something,
if you want to accomplish a task,
you'll figure out a way to do it.
People do crazy crap all the time.
My wife does that.
Yeah, I know.
I was like, wait a second.
There's a button over here.
You can do clear all.
One thing I like about
having you on the show, Max,
is that our show tends to be sort of a
halfway point between Bitcoin
and podcasting a lot of times.
And so you're going to have,
I know we have listeners who
are heavy in Bitcoin, listeners
who are heavy in podcasting and
don't know anything about Bitcoin.
And so, you know, one of
the things that we've seen
over the past year is that you
have these apps out there.
You have, you know, if you're a Bitcoiner
and you're coming to podcasting,
you're probably going to end up
somewhere in the breeze or sphinx.
The breeze or sphinx, yeah.
Yeah.
And if you're coming from
the other direction,
if you're a podcaster
coming into value for
value, you're probably going to land
on, you know, Podverse, Fountain,
Podfriend, CurioCaster,
something more of a
traditional podcast app.
So we're sort of meeting
everybody in the middle,
but I like having you
here because I think that
there's a lot of podcasters who just
still, they just do not get it.
They're still thinking
Bitcoin is quote unquote
funny money or just something like that.
Then it doesn't make any sense to them.
And, you know, I would, if you don't
mind, I would like to ask you,
because I think you're
so eloquent about this stuff.
I'd like to ask you just a
couple of basic questions
that I think other people would benefit
from that don't know a lot about Bitcoin.
Boost!
One of those, one of those things,
and these were just kind of hit me.
I was thinking last night,
if I'm a podcaster that does nothing
about cryptocurrency, what are
some things that I probably need to know?
The first one that popped
into my head was wallets.
I don't think people understand just from
hearing people talk, coins are not in the
wallet, quote unquote.
When we talk about, I have a wallet
with five Bitcoin in it, that's,
there's no coins in that wallet.
The wallet is just...
It's not bulging.
It's not bulging with Bitcoin.
Yeah, right.
The wallet just holds
the keys that tell the,
that are able to tell
the ledger that you're
the one that can spend them.
Can you sort of like,
how would you put that?
Yeah, let me give you
the quick pitch about
the entire Bitcoin infrastructure itself.
And this is coming from, and
I'll say this, Max, you're the,
Max is the developer of the
Wasabi wallet, which is a great wallet.
So he's the guy to ask
this type of stuff to.
Yeah, go ahead.
You know, fun fact, I'm a complete noob
and I can't write a single line of code.
Shit installed well on my Linux Mint, Max.
It was no problem there.
It was good.
You know, so I like to think
about, mainly use free software,
and then I find a whole bunch
of problems and I want to fix them.
And then I yell at the people that actually
do write codes to please get it done.
I'm familiar with this
type of arrangement.
Yes, yes.
I think, you know, Nopara is the
main coder behind Wasabi Wallet,
and he always likes my
very impossible feature request.
And I'm guessing that's the exact
same with you and Adam and Dave here.
Yes, we've built some
interesting products that way.
I love those products.
They will go to my grave with me.
I love them.
Yeah, yeah.
That's, by the way, how
I feel about Wasabi.
It's just a beautiful baby.
I understand that.
I totally do.
So what do you think, you know, the
wallet question, what do you think is,
what's your infrastructure thing for the
person who knows nothing about Bitcoin?
Okay, let's start from the very beginning.
And that does not yet start
with a wallet, actually.
You know, when we first want to create
a new monetary system, you know,
then first of all, we have to define the
rules of the monetary system, right?
And in Bitcoin, the rules
are defined in software.
And that package of software that
defines the rules, I mean, you can,
by the way, write this
yourself, right, from scratch,
if you have the skills.
Or, of course, you can download the
popular rule set that is Bitcoin Core.
It's a full node implementation,
which has that implementation of the
Nakamoto consensus rules, right?
These rules that tell you what
Bitcoin is valid and what is invalid.
That's ultimately what you're doing here.
And after you've defined
these rules for yourself,
and therefore you've
agreed to them, right,
by just acting them out, then you connect
to a network of random computers,
right, that all talk on the same
network and send each other
information about what Bitcoin transaction
they think are valid, right?
So everyone has their own
set of rules and everyone
kind of might have a different one,
right?
But what we talk about is not
what set of rules we have,
but rather which transactions follow
the set of rule that my
full node thinks is valid.
And then when your full node receives
this communication from others,
what it does is it verifies if the
message from the other person,
if that transaction that the other
person sent you, if that is a valid
transaction according to
your own full node rules.
And that's what it actually means
to run your own Bitcoin full node.
You literally define, verify,
and enforce the monetary rules
of your own monetary system.
Ah, that's a beautiful way to explain it.
Could I ask you something?
What kind of differences
could there be between
my node and say Dave's
node when it comes to
the rules that I have in there?
Is that like number of confirmations
or some other, I mean,
what could the real actual differences be?
Yeah, that's a great question.
And there are two different types of
changes that you could make, right?
One is, for example, you know,
your full node application has
a white mode and my full node
application has a dark mode
user interface, right?
Because I'm a dark mode
maximalist as well.
You know, that's, that's
the difference here.
We have a different piece
of software, obviously,
but it doesn't really
touch the core essence
of what makes the monetary rules,
the monetary rules, right?
So these are just like side
things in the implementation,
but it's not the consensus critical code.
Okay.
Yeah.
So it could be my node
says never make a trend,
never even approve a
transaction if you have
less than 12 volts coming in or
some, some random thing like that.
Exactly.
For example, right there,
you can do a lot of things that
might not toss you out of consensus
with other people, right?
But eventually if you change
consensus critical rules, then you,
you're no longer on the same
network of others, right?
Because there's a blocking mechanism
in there or there's like a, oh,
that guy sucks type thing.
Exactly.
So for example, right,
what if I change my full node
implementation and I broadcast the
transaction and according
to my node, it's correct.
And that transaction gives me, myself
and I a hundred billion Bitcoin.
Yeah.
You know, for my notes, it's valid
because you're rich on your node.
Yeah, exactly.
But then when I broadcast this
transaction to your node,
you read it and you're like, you idiots.
No, you delete the message.
You block my IP address and you
never, ever talk to me again.
And so that's like, um, that, that idea,
uh, that you're talking about, you,
what, what just happened there
was you forked, um, you've,
you've now gone off on your own thing and
you've become a new, a
new, a new currency.
Right.
And you're not part of, you're not part
of the Bitcoin consensus, uh, rules.
So now I think I finally understand
the 51% because if I understand it,
so you have, um,
the number of nodes, as long
as no one has more than 50%,
then it's going to be an honest system.
If someone has more than
50% of all the nodes,
then they have the capability
at least to confirm
transactions in the majority, which
the other people would might,
it might not matter anymore
if they don't confirm or am I
just talking out of my butt?
There are two separate security
vectors that we need to consider here.
Okay.
And miners and full nodes
each protect one of these.
Okay.
So the full nodes protects
the monetary rules, right?
Your full node prevents you or it, it,
it helps you to recognize
when someone pays you
with Bitcoin from a hundred
billion Bitcoin chain.
Right.
And if someone tries to pay you with
that, you're like, no, that's wrong.
Okay.
So it protects you from
giving away your actual
scarce property in exchange
for that fake Bitcoin.
Got it.
Okay.
So I'm not going to give
away my pizza for that
Bitcoin from the billion Bitcoin chain.
Right.
Um, so full nodes, uh, verify against
the debasement of the currency, right?
Against that increase in the
money supply and other things.
What miners do, and that's a very
specific other task is that in general,
anyone can write data to the
Bitcoin blockchain structure.
Now, and this data is shared,
the whole blockchain with every Bitcoin
node that is in consensus and synchronized.
But the crazy thing is
because anyone completely
anonymously can write
data to that blockchain,
right?
Well, what prevents an
idiot from just spamming
everyone with gigabytes and gigabytes
of data on that blockchain?
And the way that we do it is that we make
it difficult for anonymous miners to,
to write, to write to
the block to the chain.
Exactly.
It's difficult to find a data structure,
a block that fits a valid
pattern according to
the monetary security consensus
rules defined by the full nodes.
Right.
So miners are responsible
for writing to the Bitcoin
blockchain and therefore they protect
the censorship resistant of transactions
not being included in blocks.
Okay.
So the attack vector of
a miner is that nobody
will include your
transaction in the block.
Therefore, you're being censored.
It's the only thing.
So our Boostergram version should be,
you have to run 15 miles before you
can actually send a Boostergram.
That would be proof of work.
Exactly.
Yes.
Okay.
Your heart rate.
That's why you verify it.
Upload your heart rate.
Yeah.
That's cool.
This is very, really helpful, Max.
I mean, a lot of it's intuitive,
but hearing it in these terms,
I think for a lot of people
will make a lot of light bulbs go on.
That's really good.
Good starting point too, Dave.
One more important note to finish this up.
The only thing, literally
the only thing that
provides the censorship
resistant nature of
writing data to the Bitcoin
blockchain is the payment,
the direct payment of Bitcoin mining
fees in the transaction to the miner.
That is the only thing that
makes Bitcoin censorship
resistant from a transaction
making point of view.
Because they have an incentive to do it.
Exactly.
You can pay miners to
include your transaction and
therefore a potential
sensor of your transaction
does not get the Bitcoin that
you would pay the other miners.
So the sensor has now
the opportunity cost of
those transaction fees paid by the users
whose transactions get censored.
And that's, that's the
other reason why a lot
of people wonder what's going to happen
once all the Bitcoin is mined.
You know, once you hit 21 million,
well, there won't be any more miners.
Well, there, there will
be, but they'll just be,
their incentive will
shift and it'll happen
at some point before the end of that.
The incentive will shift from mining
to, uh, just the processing fees.
And also one nuance here, I would argue
that miners do not create Bitcoin.
Full nodes create the monetary rules
that define what a Bitcoin is, right?
And that definition includes 21 million.
That definition was set on August 3rd,
2009, and it hasn't changed, right?
So the, all 21 million
units were created with the
publication of the
software and the creation
of the Genesis block.
Oh, oh, Max, you might
be the right guy to ask.
I've always wondered why the number 21.
Great, uh, great question.
And it's, it's the result of three,
three seemingly arbitrarily
chosen variables in the system.
That's where Satoshi had
to choose any number,
but there is no correct
answer to what is the
correct number to put there.
Um, and I think he just made a gut feeling
kind of trade-off that sounded correct.
And so these three numbers are
that on average, every 10 minutes,
a Bitcoin block gets mined.
Okay.
The reason why we need latency
in between that is again,
because if everyone can write data
to the blockchain, which they can,
you know, we will be spammed.
So we need to limit the time at which a
new message, a new block can be added.
Right.
Also because latency is an issue, right?
Because it might take a couple seconds
for you to receive a newly created block.
And if there are more blocks being created
per second, then you have latency.
Yeah.
You will never be able to catch up.
Exactly.
So that 10 minute block time
was the first variable.
The second variable was a 50 Bitcoin,
um, uh, Coinbase issuance reward.
Okay.
And funnily enough, today we have
the 50th podcasting 2.0 episode.
So clearly this is the Bitcoin edition.
Yes.
Laser eyes.
Genesis reward edition.
Right.
So that was 50 Bitcoin.
Why that was chosen again,
I think it's arbitrary,
but I do think that there
was an actual mathematical
reason because of some buffer overflow,
but that's a bit too much over my head.
So I'm just going to pass on that.
Okay.
The ultimate thing is a
happening of four years.
Yeah.
Or more precisely, exactly my next,
my next question, 210,000 blocks.
Yeah.
Every then the Coinbase issuance rate,
not inflation rate, not creation rate,
the issuance rate to unlock the Bitcoin
that were predefined in Genesis, um,
will happen after every 210,000
blocks, which because of a 10
minute block time is four years.
Yes.
Yes, of course.
And now when you add all of
this together, you know,
a block every 10 minutes with 50 Bitcoin
per block happening every four,
every four years or 210,000 blocks,
when you sum all of that up, you
get to just below 21 million.
Uh, so it's actually a couple
thousand sets less than that.
Ha!
That, yeah.
And so that, you know, from a, from a
monetary theory standpoint, how much,
how much money you have in the
system is not that important.
I mean, it's the, the
quantity of money is more
of a sociological question
than an economic question.
Any amount of money is, is a
sufficient amount of money.
It's just, there are practical, you know,
there are practical
considerations as to, you know,
how much of it can be
distributed around, you mean,
you need to have at least enough money
to cover a certain set of practical
concerns within a day-to-day system.
Right.
Which is where we get millisats
and on down the line, I guess.
Yeah.
So, I mean, ultimately, I mean,
if it, if it had been, you know,
30 million or 10 million,
it probably would have been the same
difference really from a, from a,
from an economic standpoint.
Well, for me, you know, people were
sending me Bitcoin in 2009, 2010.
Um, in fact, I had quite a lot, I had
65 or so, and I sold them all at 900,
but I, but I also, I, you know,
I, I, I didn't really know what,
I wasn't really paying
attention to it, honestly.
And I, and I had a very contrary, um,
opinion of it and likened it to, uh,
beanie babies,
which, you know, I don't regret because
it makes me just that much more, uh,
in tune with, with, now that I understand
it, uh, you know, having that pain,
carrying that burden with me is good.
You're like the, you're like
the guy that quits smoking,
that gripes at everybody for
smoking, you know, for smoking.
Well, no, not quite, but
I'll take the analogy.
Thanks.
Um, you know, but, but actually the,
the real reason why it is 21
million is because Satoshi
brought us halfway to the
answer to life, the universe.
42, yes, of course.
We all know what 42 is.
But the other half, we got
to figure out ourselves.
I'd like that one, Max.
Um, but yeah, so it, it, to me, it, and
it fits in so well with value for value.
Now I understand a little bit more
about, um, you know, your own rules.
I have, I'm, I'm fully noted.
Dave's fully noted.
Uh, I, I love watching that Raspberry Pi
have it in a, in a, in a rack in my house.
It's like, oh, I look at it
through the smoky window.
It's like, yes, there it is
doing its business of the world.
Um, uh, and so, you know, I completely
understand how the mining incentives work.
And that really says a lot for the Hulk.
I mean, proof of work really is to
me, like a huge core of why it works.
Yeah, that's a, so, okay.
So I'm going to play, uh, let's
see, play Hillebrand shit coins.
Oh, is this someone I know?
Hold on a second.
It's difficult.
That's a good title.
Here we go.
It's difficult to build it on Bitcoin
because we want to do it right.
And the beauty of shit
coin is that you can just
hack on a thing for a weekend and call
it done and raise a billion
dollars in your ICO.
Yeah.
So that, so I want to talk about shit
coins that, and that is a, you know,
the moniker of everything,
essentially, that's not a Bitcoin.
Um, so, you know, this, this part,
uh, Brian of London can just,
you can turn this off or
skip it in the chapters.
What, so the difference between proof
of work, proof of stake, these,
these sorts of things,
this, this is something that
people would, would really be,
it'd be helpful for them to hear.
Do you have a thumbnail sketch
of why proof of work is,
is better than proof of stake or
these other proofing mechanisms?
Well, proof of work and
proof of stake are so
fundamentally different
crypto systems that
it's kind of impossible to compare them.
They're just different things.
And I would argue that proof of stake is,
is just not crypto dynamically secure.
It is not, it doesn't work.
It's logically impossible.
Uh, and, and there are
numerous reasons for it.
Um, one of the reasons is the, is the
bootstrapping problem, you know, um,
maybe let's first explain
what the two differences
are and also proof of
stake means that whoever has a unit of a
coin has a right to write
the next block to the chain.
And then there's some probability that
you get chosen to write the next block.
And that probability depends on how much
units you have inside that blockchain.
But the obvious problem
is how do you start that?
How does the first coin
get mined, you know?
And if the first coin gets
mined, uh, just by one person,
then he will forever be the only
one that has the right to, uh,
to actually write the chain until he
sells those units to someone else.
And that's so fundamentally
different to proof of work, right?
Because with proof of work,
anyone who has access to the
internet and to energy can create,
can write data to the Bitcoin blockchain.
You do not need to have
the internal units and
you do not need to hold it in
order to be part of the system.
And that is what makes the
Bitcoin mining censorship
resistant and permissionless
and anonymous in nature.
And without these things, this,
the censorship resistant aspects
of adding new blocks to the
chain is simply not there.
So proof of stake has zero
censorship resistance.
So that, you know, what
I've been saying is
that when it comes to the energy concerns
about Bitcoin is that this, the hash rate,
the hash power is sort of irrelevant.
It's irrelevant to what Bitcoin is.
I mean, we could, you could cut it in
half, you could cut it down to 25%,
even if there
were some rules that were enforced
globally tomorrow that cut, it said all,
all proof of work, uh,
had to be cut by 75%.
All machines have a limitation
of this many, um, kilowatt.
Yeah, exactly.
Something like that.
And then all of a sudden the hash power
was cut down, you know, 90% overnight.
Well, Bitcoin would
continue to function just
the same as it always did because the hash
power back in the day used
to be that, that little.
Now it's large because of, you know,
sometimes you wait for the
blocks a little longer.
I see the blocks taking longer,
but you're still going to get
them to every 10 minutes.
Now, sometimes I see an hour on a
block before a block before the,
since the last block.
Yeah.
I've seen that several times.
Happens quite often.
Yeah.
You're talking about how the
mempool feels and all that.
Yeah.
Exactly.
I see.
Yeah.
Um, every, every second, uh, of the day,
basically the next block is expected
to be mined within 10 minutes.
Right.
Regardless of how, how much past
the previous block was mined,
the next block is always
expected to be in 10 minutes.
Right.
But by chance it could be five seconds
or by chance it could be five hours.
And both of these cases
happen quite frequently.
Yeah.
I, uh, rewarded myself for my efforts a
couple months ago with a block clock.
Oh, such a beautiful device.
I mean, I've, if something's
handmade, what it is, you know,
they basically make them by hand.
Uh, I'll buy it.
You know, it's like I
have a Morse code key.
These that people custom made, I'm not
a great code, uh, code signer anymore,
but this block clock is,
it's a piece of art, man.
It's really, really pretty.
Yeah.
It's not prepared for Bitcoin 1 million,
not enough spaces on the
display, but otherwise.
No, no.
You see, it's, you don't
price Bitcoin in US dollar.
You price US dollar in Bitcoin.
No, I know.
How many cents is 100?
No, I understand.
And that number continues to go down.
It's true.
But I think I'll need more digits for
the, for the Satoshi display as well.
So just round it all up.
Yeah, that, that's so that,
that fundamental difference that
you're talking about between,
between the, the, you know,
alt coins, shit coins and,
and Bitcoin is something that is
just constantly, uh, bat,
bat, you know, bandied about.
And that's probably why you would,
at least my quick understanding
is that a lot of the
alt coin companies and that kind of thing,
they all seem to be
centralized around one player
instead of, you know, if whether
it's a company or a person or they,
they all seem to, you
can always say, okay, well, you can
look at that alt coin and say, well,
this is the company that's sort
of in charge of that thing.
Or this is the person who seems to be the
main player that has all the power in this
one, in, in this currency.
Yeah.
Oh yeah.
Dude, I, I, this was a
part of my learning.
My, my learning to becoming
a maxi was participating
and not completing an
ICO in the Netherlands.
And it didn't take me long to
figure out what was going on,
but I came in totally blind.
Like, oh, well, you know, when I give
you all this, it was Dench music.
I'm going to give you, uh, you know, the
stake in the Dench coins up front, uh,
once we've mined them.
Yeah.
I forgot about all that.
Oh yeah.
Yeah.
And, uh, you know, we had
artists and the whole thing.
And then it was a consultant, a
consultant from probably Switzerland,
Zook, I'm guessing.
Uh, and he was going to hook
us up with the ECR 20 token.
You know, it was all going to be good.
And the more I, you know, cause
I, I know a bit about marketing,
the more I looked at
them, it's like, this is
just a marketing thing.
What's really going on here.
And then I understand
the whole pump and dump.
And this is when ether was like
one 80, you know, and like, oh,
it was flipping out and
just has to get up to four.
What I, and I started to slowly
understand what I was in for.
And then I saw Snoop Dogg
and a couple other guys
over in Amsterdam with another company and
they're doing an ICO.
And so I'm talking to these other guys.
I'm like, okay, I see
what's going on here.
No, I can't have it.
I can't have any part of this.
This is, this will land me in jail.
And that happened to a lot of people.
Yeah.
Yeah, for sure.
And rightfully so.
You know, fraud is a serious thing.
But I didn't realize it.
And I'm not dumb, but it took me
a long time to figure out, oh,
this is basically just, you
get this, we sell it all.
And then you hope that people, you know,
maybe hold on to a little
bit and you do some more
promotion, some more news releases,
and then people buy it and you sell.
I'm like, no, this is not cool.
I mean, from a money-making
perspective, I could see that.
But yeah, I don't care about that.
You know.
Exactly.
I don't know how to make a lot of money.
I'm bad at that.
It's about project finance, you know, and,
and raising money for
a speculative venture
with a lot of counterparty risk.
Yeah.
Yes.
All, all the counterparty risk.
You know, and that's cool.
That's, that's not inherently anything
bad, but it's also not anything new.
No.
The genius of Bitcoin is that we
have a counterparty risk-free,
self-sovereign monetary asset
in cyberspace that is completely
censorship-resistant and unconfiscatable.
That is unheard of.
And that is a
once-in-a-lifetime opportunity.
I agree.
And kind of where we started this
conversation off is people are extremely
conditioned, especially
when it comes to technology.
You know, briefly recap
my favorite story from
when we had the snowmageddon here in Texas
and we were snowed in for
days and I'm out there
shoveling snow with a garden trowel.
We live in Texas after all.
I'm talking to my next door neighbor
and we're comparing notes and he says,
yeah, man, it's
been really sucky because, you know, the
power is out and I can't like the stove
so I've been going out
into the back onto the
grill because it has a
little clicker thing
and I said, dude, do you know that you
can light your stove with a match?
And I saw this, his face went white and
he's like, holy crap, I'm an idiot.
So, this kind of spoiled nature,
you know, and quite frankly,
a lot of people just don't
know how stuff works and no one
knows how the internet works.
You know, they think it's just
Facebook, Twitter or whatever.
Google is a browser.
So, when it comes to
user experience, people,
and I've examined this and I think there's
studies on it, you know, they receive
money in their wallet, which is an app,
and they feel that it's
equal to receiving an emoji.
Have it now.
I can see it.
It's right there.
It's in this phone, in
this wallet, in my app.
And that visual is there for them.
They don't see, and if
I'm good at anything,
it's I can see into how
a system works and I
see, oh, and this is the magic trick
that is performed on the front.
So, the understanding for people, I
mean, they don't, they also don't,
you know, they use Venmo.
It's like, send me a Venmo.
Boom, it's there.
They don't see what
happened in the background.
They don't see all the
different things and
the processing that takes place three days
later for settlement, and
so they never see that.
So, what we're, what I
think we're missing,
the way I see it often
is the Bitcoin education
comes from what you just did,
which I really appreciate,
and it comes from that angle, and
even today's interfaces are just kind of
becoming that Venmo-friendly, you know,
we look at strike, you know, that
Venmo-friendly type experience,
where users want to come out from
the other direction,
and they're going to miss out on all
the education and miss out on the
actual freedom they hold.
To them, it'll just be a
choice of cheaper fees,
and it would be great if we can educate
on the freedom aspect.
Yes, and it's not just freedom,
it's also security, right?
Because if you trust someone else
to take care of your money, right,
which is basically
what these custodial Bitcoin wallets
are, they are money warehouses, right?
Instead of holding...
Yes, I'm sorry to interrupt you,
but yes, this is a big problem.
People don't understand that
there's no customer support.
I mean, I can't call somebody
if I've lost my password, no.
On the other hand, and again,
apologize for interrupting,
I do think that people are learning
about security and about
cryptography with NFTs.
I think this is a fun way for
people to learn about it.
It's also a fun scam for
other people to follow up.
Of course, of course, but look, you know,
you got to learn business
sometimes by dealing
drugs, you know, that's how you
can become a good businessman.
So sometimes you got to do that.
Yeah, but arguably drugs aren't
as much of a scam as NFTs are.
Wow.
Damn, Max.
You're the right guy to have on this show.
Damn, yeah, totally, totally, totally.
But you see, just to hammer down on this
one point and the crucial difference again,
between having base money,
which is a counterparty risk-free
asset where you control it and nobody
else has a claim to it.
So that's a physical gold coin
that you hold in your hand.
You control what to do with it.
Nobody can take it away from you.
Now, that is what it is when you hold
Bitcoin on your own private keys.
The private keys are
basically a definition of
who can spend a certain chunk of Bitcoin.
And the initial definition
is a public key.
And so anyone who can
produce a signature to this
public key can spend
these Bitcoin legally.
You've got to treat this key
like it's the key to your diary.
Exactly.
It's exactly, it's kind of like the key into
your own personal gold vault, you know,
the long pin and fingerprint
and eye scan and voice check,
like all of this is basically
your private key, right?
And then magically this
door opens in cyberspace
and you can take out
the amount of Satoshis
inside that box and put it into
a new box with a new lock.
You know what's really fun?
Once a month, on the first day of every
month, I test myself on my recovery words.
Oh, your wallet, your
deterministic wallet words?
Yeah.
And once every six months or so,
I'll do a whole recovery process.
And man, when you do that, it's magic.
When you just take, I mean, you can take,
there's a lot of wallets
that'll do it now.
And you just put in your
recovery words, it goes, okay,
this schema pulls it in,
there's your Bitcoin.
And that's why I started with
that question about, about,
about wallets and how they,
and how they quote unquote
store Bitcoin, because that's,
that's the thing that I, that I think
is a very, is the most common
misconception that I hear.
And I heard it, we had a dinner with
some people the other night and I,
they were talking about
Bitcoin and they, they were talking
in this way that somebody lost their,
they had their, they said they
had their wallet on a hard drive
and they lost it and
now they can't find it.
But the, the, the, what,
those coins are not on there and
that wallet is not necessarily
on the drive, on the
hard drive and nothing.
The only thing that was on that
drive of any consequence was the,
was the blockchain.
Yeah.
And, and, and the, and the, and
the, what would you call it?
Sort of the detritus of
a, of a, of a key key.
But as long as you have a, if you have
a deterministic wallet, you can re,
you know, re, restate your
words, that big batch of words
that comes up in a matrix.
When you create your wallet,
you can restate those words,
it will regenerate the key.
And now you have your wallet
back because all you've
done is you just restored, you've restored
the key, which is the thing
that tells the blockchain
ledger that you are the
person who has the rights
to spend this Bitcoin on the ledger.
So is that pretty accurate?
But people, but people gravitate
towards wallet, you know, it's like,
it's understandable.
Apple with their, with their, their
iOS wallet, where you put your, your,
your value cards and your credit
cards and your vaccination cards
and you put all that in your wallet.
I mean, we can't fight that.
I don't think.
Yeah.
And maybe the term key chain would
have been the better analogy, right?
Because it really is that the
coins are in the blockchain.
And you know, the
beautiful thing is you get
to look at them for all eternity and, and
marvel in, in your mistake of
losing your private keys to them.
You know, if your boat sings
with a horde of gold on deck,
at least you no longer have
to look at the gold.
You get to look at that all day long.
Yeah.
So when, so when I fire up, when I
download Wasabi wallet, fire it up,
it gives me a bunch of words, you
know, save those words, you know,
I can go to another machine, download,
download, download Wasabi,
fire up that wallet,
put those words in and
I'm back in business.
There's no, there's no
problem there because what,
what happens on the blockchain is, uh,
you know, I send you some,
some Bitcoin and I just, uh,
I have just signed the transactions
on the, on the, on the blockchain
to tell it that this, uh,
that you now have the
ability to spend this coin.
The coins aren't physically
located anywhere.
They're just in the ledger that way.
Exactly.
One key insight is that
you need both a wallet
as well as a full note in
order to spend your Bitcoin.
Right.
Because if you want to
create a transaction that
spends a certain amount of coins, well,
first you need to find
out in the blockchain,
where is a coin and on
which address and with
how much Bitcoin is in there.
Right.
You need to know the exact
reference or the exact
location of a certain chunk of Bitcoin
in the blockchain, the so-called
unspent transaction output or UTXO.
And that is what your
full note is used for.
Right.
That's why they're all sitting
around there, swimming around.
Exactly.
My UTXOs.
My little fishes.
Your wallet talks to your full note,
finds out which coins belong to you.
Right.
And then it shows you your total balance,
the sum of the value of
Satoshis of all these
coins that are on your public keys, right?
On your addresses.
All right.
No, I'm sorry.
Your wallet signs the
spending transactions,
which takes one or more of these chunks of
Bitcoins, these coins that you have in a
single, in the input side of a transaction.
So you destroy the coins that
you have received previously.
And in the output side of the
transaction, you put the addresses,
which is kind of the
destination or the public key,
which is the one that has now
the Satoshis locked into it.
And so whoever then knows the private key
to that new public key of that new address
can spend that new coin that
you're about to create.
And your wallet is used to
sign this data structure
of inputs and outputs
with your private keys
and then to broadcast the
signed and final transaction
to the entire Bitcoin
network and ultimately
to Bitcoin miners so that they include this
transaction in one of the next blocks.
Oh, man.
So I'd like to move to
the Lightning Network.
How much do you know about it?
I love it.
I really love it, man.
You know, I, it blew my
mind probably even more
than when I first kind of started to get
a glimpse of Bitcoin
because it's like, oh shit,
I completely underestimated what this
Bitcoin machine is doing.
And it opened up this whole
new level of possibility.
And, you know, again, I was way too
early and reckless with this on mainnet,
you know, booting up in November 2017.
I don't think I've ever done
anything ever on test net.
Hardcore main all the, all the way.
That makes mistakes memorable.
Oh yeah.
Somebody, I think it was Desiree Dickerson
was saying on Twitter a while back,
she's like, you know, people, people
sometimes will dabble and they'll say, well,
I'm just going to send
a little bit of Bitcoin as a test, you know,
over to this other wallet or something.
And she, she's like, they don't
understand that every time you send any,
you're sending all of it.
And so that's, yeah.
The test, test, even, you know, mainnet
is always fraught with, you know,
fraught with danger.
Yeah.
You always need to spend a whole
chunk of the Bitcoin, right?
You cannot crack a coin in half, kind of.
You need to put the whole coin into the,
not 100 million sats as
in one whole Bitcoin, but
the whole chunk of a hundred
thousand sats or whatever it is.
Yeah.
Everything in your wallet, basically.
So if you have, so with, with Lightning,
all that stuff that was just,
you know, that you just went over and sort
of did with the basics of, of blockchain,
of the core Bitcoin protocol
and the way Bitcoin works on its
fundamental level, Lightning,
Lightning solves a bunch
of those fundamental issues
that come from scaling.
It's really, Lightning just exists to
solve the scaling problem and the scale,
and I would say that the scaling
problem can be summed up
by saying that there's just never enough
block size to fit all the
transactions in, uh, into,
into it in order to make things snappy
and quick and scalable to a global, um,
Visa MasterCard style
transaction processing system.
So something had to be, something
had to be created that would off,
that would offload that transaction processing
into a sort of a layer above Bitcoin.
Is that fair?
Yeah, that's exactly spot on.
And one more nuance is that
Bitcoin, in my opinion,
was never designed for a payment system.
Making payment system is easy.
Show me an e-cash, 1983, perfectly private
transaction system, problem solved.
That was never difficult.
Difficult thing was to
verify payments and Bitcoin
is a verification machine of payments,
right?
And the way that it does it is by
incredible, um, unnecessary, uh, redundancy.
You know, everyone verifies every
single transaction that's had,
that has ever happened.
That's never going to work for
a payment network at scale.
Exactly.
Just by the base concept
of if everyone needs to
verify everything and
including if you want
to verify a transaction today,
you need to verify the entire
blockchain since Genesis,
right?
You cannot just verify current
UTX OSET without the history.
So, you know, that's a big problem.
And the idea of the
Lightning Network is now to
find a crypto-dynamically
secure way to send
satoshis in a way that you don't need
to tell everyone that you sent them.
Yet still, despite only telling
the sender and receiver
and the few people on the route about
that you're moving these, these
satoshis from one entity to another,
it is still crypto-dynamically
secure, meaning that nobody
can steal the money from you.
It is still non-custodial.
It is still censorship resistant and
it is still, well, unconfiscatable.
That's, that's, that's the beauty.
And it also adds, I would say, I
mean, correct me if I'm wrong,
but the other benefit of Lightning
is that it also adds better privacy to
Bitcoin than Bitcoin has in and of itself.
It opens up a whole bunch
of additional problems
that you have to worry about if
you want to do privacy right.
In, or in other words, in theory,
Lightning is great for privacy
just by the fact that you
don't tell everyone
about every transaction.
That's better, right?
But it's such a complex system and it's
so, man, like privacy is a bitch, really.
And especially if you want to do it right.
That's a t-shirt, t-shirt, hold
on, it is a t-shirt, t-shirt.
Yeah.
So, you know, by the way, humble shill,
but I made a join the
WasabeeCast podcast with
Istvan Serres about the privacy
of the Lightning Network.
And we go through a lot of
potential attack vectors
that can reduce your privacy in Lightning.
The cool thing is we know about a lot of
them and we know how to fix most of them.
So in theory, it's great.
It's just over the last
four to five years,
nobody had the patience
to implement it properly
and it will probably take
another long time before
a truly cryptographically sound privacy
system on Lightning can be implemented.
So you would be the right
guy to ask about this.
So one of the things that
we're running up against
as a challenge with the mechanism we've
chosen for value for value
streaming payments is Keysend.
Keysend requires always on
for transmission and receival
or at least for receiving,
for transmitting.
You know, you have to at
least have synced the
graph and just a whole host
of problems on mobile.
So we're seeing the most
uptake come from podcast
apps that use a custodial solution.
And we honestly don't see any other
way, certainly at the moment.
So I'm just curious about your input
on that, your thoughts in general.
Yeah, the quick and easy path, right?
It's so much easier to
trust a bank and to lay
out or to outsource all the security and
system reliability,
critical infrastructure out
to a trusted third party who knows what
they're doing, who are reputable, right?
Who might not even want to run away
with the money and all of that.
That's so much easier.
And you can build a UX that's infinitely
easier than trying to design a
non-custodial and secure
and private system from scratch
with a beautiful user interface.
And again, I cannot under,
I cannot overstate how massive the UX win
of wallets like Breeze or Moon or Phoenix.
No, I totally agree.
100%.
But you're right.
It takes a massive effort, massive effort.
And, you know, Roy and all
of Breeze, God bless them,
they've staked the company on this.
I mean, they're in all the way.
This is no joke.
Many Bitcoiners are in all the way.
Yes, I know.
Well, but, you know, it was based on
some of the stuff we had done, you know,
a little bit of scotch
tape over the holes in it.
You know, I thought it was quite
a leap of faith, quite honestly.
I thought it was incredible.
So, yes, and they have, I mean, right
now, I don't know, last I checked,
but their stuff was even syncing the
graph, was overheating iOS machines.
There's a lot that goes on there.
So, yeah, ultimately,
that's the way to go.
I think that where we've compromised, at
least for now, is the amount, you know,
the values, you know, if these
wallets have to be moved
out to your own non-custodial solution, if
you have it, or wherever else you want,
if we keep that low, then, you know,
then the concept of, are we a bank
or are we a till, is, you know,
there's a little difference there.
And so, yeah, here's the risk.
Here's the total risk to
you, person using it,
and here's the total
risk to us providing it.
Well, I mean, it's case in point, Sphinx.
I mean, like James Cridland,
he was an early guy in Sphinx,
and he can't get his sats out
now because something with, you know,
he's got one of their nodes
running on their systems
with their channels, and it's
just not working in the channel.
There's something wrong with the
channel, and he's just stuck.
He can't get any sats out of that thing.
So, I mean, they're seeing, you know, the
non-custodial, the custodial solution, you
know, does have problems,
but then you had, you know,
the only mitigation strategy for
now is just to keep the limits low and
sweep that stuff out to, you know,
to your own system on a regular basis.
Exactly.
The beauty of a free market is that
the client has the power to choose,
and then individual subjective preferences
will be different for each one.
And the risk and security trade-off
that everyone chooses is independent.
And, you know, that's all right.
You know, banking is great.
Money warehouses are great.
Bitcoin doesn't eliminate banking.
Bitcoin eliminates central bank
and the creation of base money.
But, you know, banking
services that use modern
base money like Bitcoin
are going to be very
successful and vitally important
for any advanced economy.
That's a good point.
Yeah, that's a really great point,
actually, because then you have, you know,
as long as you
will, you have to even take that to apps
like Cash App or something like that.
You know, you can buy
Bitcoin and I have a weekly
purchase of Bitcoin for a
long time through there.
And then just occasionally, because
they allow you to move it out,
occasionally I just move
it to my own wallet that I control.
And so I'm getting the benefits of
this sort of that temporary storage.
Exactly.
And it's like, I've been doing
that for years with Coinbase,
although I'm going to switch
now because they're just too expensive.
Hashtag delete Coinbase.
Yeah.
Yeah, I know.
I know.
I love the peer-to-peer market.
That's my favorite.
I love it.
Blue Wallet has that.
Bisk is a phenomenal piece of software
you guys should be checking out.
Fisk?
Bisk.
B-I-S-K dot network.
Oh, Bisk.
The Bitsquare network.
Funnily, the Square
Twitter company launched a
copyright infringement
suit on them because
it was called Bitsquare in the past.
Typical.
But in any case, this is
a self-hosted exchange,
meaning that you run an
exchange node, so to say.
Right.
And you connect in a peer-to-peer
decentralized system
to other potential nodes who offer trades
to buy or sell Bitcoin for
anything that you could imagine.
Yeah.
And because of the use of Bitcoin
multi-signature and, again,
a cryptodynamically secure protocol
of Bisk, a trading protocol, so to say,
there has not been a single theft
or breach of contract in Bisk.
These are collateralized trades.
I love this.
Yeah, yeah, because there's
some kind of escrow
system that kicks in before the
trade settles or something.
Exactly.
So when I make an offer that, hey,
I have one Bitcoin and I
want to sell that for some
fiat fund coupons, then first I deposit
10% of that into a multi-signature,
right, into this two of
two multi-signature.
And later, I broadcast this offer
to anyone out there, right,
through this Tor network
and peer-to-peer network of Bisk, and
anyone can talk to my hidden service,
tick me up on
this offer by sending 10% of the trade
value into this collateral as well.
So both of us have 10%, can be 50%,
that's again up to the individual
traders of involuntary action, right?
And then after this,
I send my whole one Bitcoin into
this trade deposit as well, right?
So I have the 10% collateral at first
and then later the whole trading amount.
Then you can verify on
the Bitcoin blockchain
with your own Bitcoin
full note that someone
has just paid one Bitcoin
into this multi-signature
scheme where you control one
out of two keys from, right?
And at that point, because
you've verified and
you already have kind of partial ownership
over this, you can send your fiat to my
bank account or hand me over the cash.
You know, or whatever it is that we trade.
And as soon as I receive it, I sign
that two out of two multi-signature.
You sign that two out
of two multi-signature.
You get 1.1 Bitcoin,
the one Bitcoin that I traded you plus
the 0.1 Bitcoin security deposit,
and I get my 0.1 security deposit back.
But if any one of us runs away, you know,
either you run away after
I deposit the one Bitcoin
or I run away after you send me those,
whatever, how many fun coupons that's worth,
then we have kind of these
pre-signed transactions
and a way to recoup the
money by an arbitrator,
you know, by this private
arbitration service, basically,
provided by a person of your choosing.
It's a convoluted protocol and
crazy in the nuances, but it works.
And even the UI is not
that difficult nowadays.
And so what power does the arbitrator
have over the transaction?
They can make the final determination
whether it should happen or not?
So I will explain the
current model, how it is.
It was different in the past.
But right now, so it's a two
out of two multi-signature
between buyer and seller of this trade.
But before anyone deposits money into
this two out of two multi-signature,
kind of similar to a
lightning channel, actually,
the other party creates, or we both
create a pre-signed refund transaction
that gets valid after two weeks.
Yeah, I was going to say time-based.
Okay, I got it.
Yep, I got it.
So a time-locked pre-signed
refund transaction that
goes to the public key of the arbitrator.
It's like the HTLCs? Is that similar?
It's similar but not exactly
the same because HTLCs
are used so that you can route payments
through multiple payment channels,
and that's not needed here.
My God.
Is anyone still listening?
Hello, is anyone still
listening to this podcast?
Hello, hello, hold on a second.
Boost.
Yeah, okay.
Boost for max.
Yeah, okay, so I'll just throw
a couple of things in here
because people, some terminology that
people are not going to understand.
Multi-signature.
Remember we talked about wallets,
and a wallet is just keys that allow
you to spend Bitcoin on the ledger.
A multi-sig wallet is the same concept,
except now you have two sets of
keys that can validly spend, right?
Exactly.
And you can make arbitrary
thresholds here, right?
You can have a 1 out of 2, a 2 out
of 3, a 5 out of 7, a 11 out of 15.
I think that's currently the largest,
or 15 out of 15 is the
potentially largest that's
currently supported.
And that would be something,
imagine a situation where you
have a large company and you say,
okay, I need five, I've got
a board of this many people,
and we're going to secure our Bitcoin
funds with a 5 out of 11 wallet,
and then you would have five
potential signature, you know,
signing keys in that wallet.
And so you could say, well,
it's going to take this many people in
order to approve the sending of funds.
Exactly.
And you can even have a
timely decay in here, right?
So that any time, 5 out of 11 can spend.
But if after two years, the money was
not yet moved, a 3 out of 5 can spend.
Yeah, this is how I want to
do my will for the kids.
Exactly.
This is how you do your trust.
Yeah, have the decay.
Hey, screw you kids.
Sorry.
Look, here are the keys.
I just ate them.
Can't do anything.
No, no.
They still have the keys.
No, but I just ate mine, so
I can't change it anymore.
I ate my keys.
They just sit around and wait
for their keys to get money.
One sat.
What a surprise that would be.
Oh, dad's been dead for 10 years and
finally, oh my God, like 50 sats.
What a bastard.
Of course, by then it'll be worth,
yeah, I know, it'll be worth millions.
That's what I was about to say.
I know, I know.
I can't even mester them
from the grave, damn it.
Damn you, Bitcoin.
You know, that's the even crazier idea.
What if you can memorize 12 words
in your reincarnation after death?
That's like a cheat code for a
head start in the next session.
That's why I practice every month, Max.
You never know.
I really like that.
That's the above, down, down,
left, right, left, right.
That's the cheat code,
ultimate cheat code entry.
Exactly.
That is fantastic.
You know, can you, maybe that will
actually be a proof, you know,
that the life after death.
I have proof of life,
proof of previous life.
Only, only if I'm assured
that when we come back,
all this coronavirus crap will be gone.
That's all I care about.
Well, if Bitcoin was
the only money we used,
all those problems would probably go away.
We'd be living in a value
for value world, I think.
That's the vision.
Do we want to thank some people?
Since we've been talking
about Bitcoin and Lightning,
let's thank people for
sending us cuck bucks,
or as Max just called
it, fiat funny money.
What did you call it?
Fiat fun coupons.
You know, it's like going to Disneyland.
You don't hoard the
Disneyland tokens, you know.
You spend your money on Disneyland tokens
for exactly the amount that you want to,
you know, spend it in the fun park.
And same as it.
Of course, you don't hold
your wealth in fiat.
That's ridiculous.
You know, you hold all
your wealth in sets,
and then you buy exactly as much fun
coupons as you need to buy your stake,
you know.
Wow.
Where have you been all my life, Max?
In cyberspace.
All right.
This is the value for value
project, the entire project.
And we're probably going to be hitting you
a little harder as we go down the road,
as we've been looking at the cost
of running and what we can provide.
But right now, we're, I think, even keel.
We're doing pretty good.
And it is all because of the support we
get from, and I don't like this word,
but it is truly a good.
My astrologer, I never
hired an astrologer,
but one of our producers on the No
Agenda show, she does that for a living.
She sent me something today, like Uranus.
I swear to God.
This favors you, which is
always a fun thing to say.
And then, you know, and this
is why you build community.
You don't even...
This is not a real, this
is not a real astrologist.
No, no, yes, he is.
You've been scammed.
No, no, no.
This is Penny.
Hold on a second.
Don't make me...
I didn't know that Uranus
even knew about me.
That's the only part of me
that knew about you, Max.
Hold on a second.
Yeah, I can go on all day,
ladies and gentlemen.
Here.
She says, Penny.
She says, you don't understand.
No, what you've done can't be understated.
You've created community.
You've shaken off illusions.
Uranus, the planet of...
Uranus, the planet...
I'm like a five-year-old.
I'm sorry.
I know.
I can't help it myself.
But it gets better.
The Uranus, the planet of individuation,
awakening freedom and
friendship, loves you.
So my Uranus loves you.
And there you go.
Ha, ha, I got you again.
ISO bombshell.
Oh, wait.
You got ISOs here today, huh?
Bombshell.
Okay.
That goes into the rack.
Hold on.
We'll put that in there.
The bombshell into the rack.
Bombshell.
All right.
It works.
Anyway, my point being that
everyone's building this together.
And we're doing what we do.
And you do what you do.
Time, talent, or treasure.
All of the above help.
And we really do like thanking,
as we discussed earlier,
the people who supported us financially
with their fiat fund coupons.
And sats.
But we'll get to those as well.
Ben and Alberto from RSS.com gave us $450.
Oh, yeah.
Wow.
Fantastic.
Thank you.
These guys get it.
Hey, Dave and Adam, we're in for the node.
Expanding the reach, resolve,
and revolution of podcasting 2.0 is
something we love to help out with.
V4V is revolutionary.
And we hope to always be on
this side of innovation.
Cheers from your buddies at RSS.com.
Cheers, guys.
And that's exactly, funny enough,
Dave, Eric, and I were talking, like,
we're going to need a substantial
amount of cash to fund a node
if we're going to be helping
with hosting podcaster wallets.
That's the biggest thing is, like,
you know, we've got to have 10,
20 grand to put up to
really, if we want to make it go smooth.
No, no.
But wait a second.
You only need to provide the
money if the podcaster gets paid.
You don't pay the podcaster.
No, I know.
No, no, no.
No, I understand.
It's, we actually like it because
we're going to turn that into Bitcoin.
It just sits there and it just,
you know, it's running the node,
but you've got to have it first.
Let's see.
Mike Clark gave us $50.
Thank you, Mike.
And he says, excited to hear
you adopt my suggestion.
Oh, yes, yes, yes.
Okay.
So, Mike is the guy that
coined the phrase Boostergram.
Excited to hear you adopt
my suggestion, Boostergram,
into the official podcasting 2.0 lexicon.
Hold on a second.
What is Mike's last name?
Mike's last name is Clark.
I want to codify this.
Mike Clark.
His handle is Aerostatica on
the Mastodons and the Twitter.
What is it?
Aerostatica.
A-E-R-O-S-T-A-T-I-C-A.
Okay.
So, the reason why I'm
asking all this is I know
who came up with the term podcasting and
that story has gotten convoluted,
particularly if you take it into
the context of what we were
actually doing at the time.
And so, I want to make sure that Mike
Clark, Mike Clark, known as Aerostatica.
Aerostatica or Aerostatic?
A-E-R-O-S-T-A-T-I-C-A.
So, Aerostatica.
Oh, Aerostatica.
Okay.
That he came up with the term Boostergram.
And I'm going to come up
with the term for when
you send something above the
block level and it's a nasty one.
It's called a Booster Slam.
Put that in here.
Adam Curry.
August 13th, 2021.
Someone's going to come up with
a way to make a Booster Slam.
I'm not sure what, but it's
going to be something.
You've got to put that on the blockchain.
Otherwise, it never happened.
Yeah.
There you go.
Good point.
It's like the old days
when you want the old
wives tale that you
could protect yourself,
like your invention, by mailing
the schematics of it to yourself.
Yeah.
Don't open the envelope.
Email it to yourself or mail it.
Yeah.
Mail it through the post, postal service.
Just one of many contributions I make,
streaming sats and evangelizing everywhere.
Sincerely, Aerostatica.
Thank you very much.
Thank you, Mike.
Let's see.
The last of the weekly PayPal donations.
Let's make sure this is not anonymous.
Yeah.
Derek Birch.
Hello, Adam and company.
I'm a Joe to no to mo to 2.0 listener.
Oh, I like it.
I truly believe that podcasting and crypto
will help save the world's problems.
Thanks for combining the two.
Love the chemistry between you guys.
No Cuomo.
Please defragment me, Derek.
That's a good one.
Okay.
So now we got Boostergrams.
All right.
Let's see here.
And there's a couple
of make-goods in here.
Hold on.
Let's look for the
international listeners.
And now, as the French say,
it is time for Le Boost.
Le Boost.
These are so good, man.
Le Boosts feel better.
Trip Scott.
We need, you know what we need?
We need Das Boost.
See, I'm embarrassed because Max is a
German who speaks English better than I do.
This is, I'm already very eloquent.
I know.
I noticed that too.
I'm like, damn, man.
The guy's got using vocabulary.
Does he not know this is a podcast?
We just go to, just up talk and it's fine.
I don't yet have that Texas Throttle.
Yeah.
Oh, well, here's a little lesson.
Partner, how long has it been
since you clicked Boost?
That's too long.
There you go.
Dreb Scott.
My profile.
He says, 20,133 sats.
Oh, wow.
He says, my profile pic is Mourn from
the Star Trek Deep Space Nine TV show.
He was a recurring
character that never spoke.
Kind of reminds me of myself.
Go podcasting.
All right.
Yes.
Oh, I got it.
Sorry.
I got a failure here.
Go podcasting.
Boost.
There we go.
And then he followed that up
with another 20,133 sats.
He just says, go podcasting.
And I'm happy to do it again.
Go podcasting.
Dreb Scott, who also, this is
also kind of self-boost-elation.
Oop, I made another one.
He's self-boost-elating.
Dreb Scott gets 5% right in the value
block because he does all the chapters.
And he does outstanding.
He does outstanding job.
Let's see.
He had something the other day
with the Dukes of Hazzard.
With the podcasting 2.0 logo.
Yes.
The podcasting index logo.
But it was, oh, he had a
funny thing about it, too,
which should have been
the title of the show.
Let's see.
Boosts of Hazzard.
Was it something like that?
It was better than that.
Anyway.
Thank you very much, Dreb.
Let's see.
Kyle Hebert.
50,050 sats.
Whoa.
Making it rain Satoshis.
I'm beyond honored you used the
clip of me saying boost repeatedly.
Thanks so much for the name drops and
for taking podcasting into the future.
Also, I'm oddly addicted to the
sound of Dave crinkling paper.
If you ever need voiceover, I'm your guy.
Yeah.
I'm sure that's a thing.
This, like, AMSR type thing.
Oh, crinkle paper for me.
Well, he's a sound guy.
You should try it on your OnlyFans, Dave.
See how it works.
Oh, here we go.
Wait.
Is that from the hypersonic boombox?
I always say it wrong.
The subatomic boombox.
I can't help myself.
That's not even right, either.
It's the intergalactic boombox.
Intergalactic boombox.
There you go.
Yeah.
I-B-B.
Kyle is a professional voice actor.
No, he's got a great voice.
He's a boomer.
He does, like, anime
and all kinds of stuff.
I've always wanted to do that.
I could never break in.
I never, I never.
John used to coach me on the
show when I got auditions.
I had an agent.
I never got one single gig
for a voiceover, ever.
Yeah, I know why.
It's because John gave you
the same advice every time.
Uh, sound like a surfer dude.
That's all he ever said.
You're right.
That's not, it's not happening.
Didn't work.
Selonomics, 1000 sats.
He says, um, hi guys, enjoying your
contributions to the future of podcasting?
An uncensorable infotainment.
I noticed a bug on the
Breeze app on Android.
Oh, no.
Uh-oh.
Uh, the podcasting 2.0 show
always seems to end violently.
Oh, wait, we already read this.
Yeah, right.
We had that one.
Oh, okay, wait, forget it.
Act like it didn't exist.
Okay, didn't happen.
Um...
That's a double spending attempt, right?
Yeah, right there.
Denied.
You broke the rules in my node, Jones.
Uh, okay.
Now, this is a definite
make good because, um,
Kieran from the Mere
Mortals podcast, he sent
two big donations, two big
boostergrams, and it was in,
it was on the week that our cert
expired for LNCLI, and I was trying, and
I missed him, so I've corrected that,
so I had to go back and fish him out and
decode him by hand on the command line.
Um, so 50,000 sats from Kieran, and
he says, thanks for the shout-out.
You picked the best part
at the start, Dave.
Bloody hilarious.
I think he's referring to the
clip that I played with him.
Yes, yes.
Uh, I did a substandard
job of explaining 2.0,
but have played around a lot since then,
so later episodes give
more credit to all the fun
apps and just how excited
this has made me.
I can confirm that the
background noise that you
heard was indeed the Australian ambiance.
Don't feel it as an
Aussie podcast unless we,
unless at least one spider
attacks us midway through.
Actually, I've caught
this on our video twice.
Jeez, I thought he was kidding.
No, no, no.
That's ridiculous.
Uh, would send it through if you could
also attach pics and vids to boostergrams.
Oh, okay.
Now we're getting fancy, huh?
Nah, it's scary, too.
That's getting a little scary.
Yeah.
Even, even I want to block
if that's going to happen.
Yeah, I don't want dick pics
through the boostergram.
My, my experience is
related to MTV days, 1988.
I had 12 mail bags in my dressing
room filled with postcards and, um,
envelopes with pictures.
Oh.
Oh, yeah.
I bet there was bad stuff in there.
It was, um, but it was actually, I was so
bored sometimes waiting between takes.
And I, the audio guy and I
were friends, Rick Kellman,
he died a couple of years ago.
And I would do audio.
We wouldn't tell anyone.
I'd just slip into the booth and I'd just
be doing audio for MTV and he'd be taking
a dump in my dressing room
reading through mail.
And he'd be like, oh, I found some
cool pictures here, this one.
And so that's, that's, and I spent
weeks like that in the boring days.
Would it have changed anything
if you would have gotten
paid for every time you read the message?
Um, you know, oh, well,
that's a good question, man.
You know what?
It's the same thing because they actually,
you send me an envelope and you've,
you've written a letter and you've
taken a picture in front of the mirror.
You've gotten it developed.
We didn't have digital cameras back then.
You took it to the photo mat of you,
you know, naked in front of the camera,
in front of the mirror.
You mailed it to me.
I call that proof of work.
So right there, I knew there
was value inside, baby.
You know, I didn't know what kind of
value, but I knew it was in there.
It's value to somebody.
Yeah.
It's the basics of spam
protection, at least.
Yeah, no, yeah, absolutely.
But your point is well made.
And of course, you know, ever since we
started playing around with Sphinx chat,
I was sold on the idea.
I mean, I can't wait to see first person to
implement like an extra piece of content
or something you can unlock by tapping
on a link in a, in a podcast chapter.
You know, there might
just be a button there.
You can just tap it and then a link
appears and you're good to go.
I mean, I see all of this.
We just don't have the
tools yet, you know,
but it's guys like RSS.com and Buzzsprout.
And, you know, there's a lot
of guys who are, you know,
I know they're following along,
but I know that we can get to
a more creative point at some,
somewhere in the future where these
authoring tools will become available.
Yeah, for sure.
And I mean, already now we have
some tech for this that are, again,
mainly Bitcoin banks, like
for example, LNTX bot.
For Telegram, a Lightning chat bot
that can do all types of cool stuff,
like hiding messages and they're
only revealed after payments.
Or you toss some stats to a
participant in the chat or,
or you make a lottery and it's a game of
chance, likely illegal to, to whomever.
So a lot of these things work at
least on the custodial front.
But I think, you know, again,
with more time and by the way,
check out stuff like Lightning Network
offers a new Bolt 13 standard,
which I think has the potential to
include a lot of these added things.
Because a core component of that addition
is that sender and receiver have inside
the Lightning Network, but
without actually sending payment,
they can send back and forth
multiple rounds of communication,
nicely inbuilt into the protocol.
So that I think will be
super useful for you guys.
Hey, Max, can I ask you something?
Are you, have you been invited to the
Lightning Round Tables, Lightning,
Lightning the company is
doing, Lightning Network?
Lightning Labs.
Lightning Labs, I mean, yeah.
I think I've been on a couple, but not in
the, in the short recent time, actually.
Because there's one that, that we
participated in last time and,
and there's a couple coming up.
And I think it would be really beneficial
to podcasting 2.0 if you have the time and
if you feel like it, if you join there.
Because like what I just heard
about the Lightning Network offers,
I didn't know about this.
And I think you understand
very well what we're doing.
And man, having some of
your brain power on that
and being able to feed
that back into labs.
Although I don't know how much they
actually, I don't want to say care, but,
you know, we're just over here
and they're happy to have us.
They're working on scaling and
all kinds of other things.
But, you know, just to be able to, to have
your brain power interface over there.
Yeah, I, I, for sure do my
best with, with shilling.
I mean, you know, I'm
shiller brand after all.
I shill a lot of brands.
But, uh, another humble shill, uh,
is to the join the Wasabicas podcast again
with a episode with Rusty Russell from
Blockstream, who's
working on Sea Lightning,
different Lightning implementation,
actually the first one that I was using.
And he is pioneering that
bold 12 offers standard.
And the episode is all about that.
So, uh, and I also bring up all
the great feature requests, uh,
that podcasting 2.0, uh, would benefit.
What's the name of the podcast?
Join the Wasabicas, a
Bitcoin privacy podcast.
Fortunately, you cannot
find it on Apple iTunes.
Quote unquote, unfortunately,
I'm happy about, about that,
but at least it's in
the podcast index.org.
Yeah, you don't need to be anywhere else.
That shit doesn't work anymore.
It doesn't.
You can get, you can be over
there, but your episode may not.
Yeah, you're, you're, you're always
72 hours behind, but you know, okay,
you can be over there if you want.
I'm going to temp, I'm going to temper
my criticism of that scene is how we've,
uh, we've been having
that problem lately too.
So I'm going to, I'm going to
not throw stones, but, uh, okay.
Well, at least you're failing
with the best of them.
True.
And, and at least, uh, you know, they get,
they make a million dollars
every eight minutes.
We make, uh, you know, we make
significantly less than that.
No, we make a, we, I think
we make an average of what?
Maybe three, two Satoshis a minute.
That's, uh, eventually
that'll be a million dollars.
Well, yeah, I do just want to say that is
the weirdest part of this whole project.
We are just stacking sats, everything
from the show, every, every fee,
everything just sits on our node.
And what's, what's kind of weird
is, you know, I use Zap Wallet.
So I look at, uh, I look
at how many sats we have.
Uh, and underneath it has
a little dollar amount.
And of course, when, uh, when the, when
the dollar weakens against, uh, Bitcoin,
and then you see all of a sudden that
number goes up, it's just like this,
this weird feeling of, you
know, we don't even know if,
if we're ever going to make anything,
if we're ever going to
withdraw any money at all.
But somehow, if we keep this going,
this just might have some value coming
back to us in the future, you know,
because we're just stacking
sats every single minute.
And it's one or two, it's, it's, you know,
sometimes it's bigger if it's a part
of a boost, but it's really, it's,
yeah, it feels so good.
I'm just so into that, you know, and
it's not how much it's just, I see,
because every single transaction is
someone saying, I like this podcast.
I like what all this shit is doing.
And I know that the
podcast app got the same
experience and the
podcaster and we got it.
And that just makes me feel good.
Ah, so much.
You know, there's this Bitcoin
story about the Bitcoin pizza.
And it's always told that this one guy
bought two pizzas for 10,000 Bitcoin.
And everyone's like, oh, how crazy that
guy spent the Bitcoin way too early.
And I'm like, no, no, no.
You're looking at it from the wrong way.
It's all about the genius
merchants who provided
two pizzas to a guy that really wanted it.
And was willing to pay 10,000
damn Bitcoin for that.
That entrepreneur is my hero.
And with podcasting 2.0, you can be the
guy getting two whole sats every minute.
You know, that's generational wealth.
And that's just, that's incredible.
You know, you help people earn
Bitcoin every single day.
That is so unspeakably beautiful.
Yeah, I love you.
I love you, Max.
I love you, Dave.
You know who else loves you?
Excuse me.
Hello, I'm waiting.
I love you, Dave.
Oh, yeah.
Damn, boys.
I still didn't hear you say it, but I do.
Max, like I do.
That's important to me.
I don't throw out my I
loves you's like that.
And if I don't get it back,
I'm very weird about it.
I was about to segue into
Kieran's donation where he says,
got to spread the love across
both Boostergram sites because he went, he
went from CurioCaster over to PodFriend.
Yeah, I do that too.
And gave them both.
Yeah.
Although I do.
Let's see.
Although I do love the POOST moniker.
So I'll claim this as a six-figure boost.
You'd be very wealthy.
You'd be very wealthy people
if you were converting
these sats to Australian dollars
on the one-to-one like I am.
Well, as we're just talking,
you know, give us a few years.
His total Boostergram amount between
these two donations is 97,500 sats.
Holy shit.
Which is basically like
$8 million in Australia.
Which buys you an ice cream cone.
This is my current episode.
So once I've reached
up to the present day,
I should have boosted
and streamed enough to
claim a 2.0 t-shirt.
Oh, yeah.
Totally.
Absolutely.
Yeah.
Send me your stuff.
Seeing your evolution through
the episodes is fantastic.
There is certainly enough coding
jargon talk to drive me off.
But the entertainment from your skill,
humor, and hard work keeps me hooked.
A testament to both of
you as podcasters as well
as everyone else for making this happen.
Go podcasting.
Go.
Hold on a second.
Go podcasting.
So a couple things.
It's really nice, first of all.
Second, Dave Jones, you are
an outstanding podcaster.
I want you to know that.
I love you, Adam.
I love you too, Dave.
No, but you started right off.
You came in.
And it's like that chair had always
had your butt imprint in it.
I'm not kidding.
It's a delight.
The way we work together with guests.
Oh, yeah.
No, I'd do a podcast with you anytime.
I'd do one with you anytime, too.
Well, of course.
Actually, I do.
I'm the podfather.
Of course you would.
What are you talking about?
Well, I got to say it out loud, though.
And then the other thing I was going to
say, kudos to, let's see, who has it now?
Fountain and CurioCaster, now
that they have a transaction log,
they're working on some of that.
That's really cool and helpful.
It is.
I like that.
I mean, Breeze has that, of course.
I like seeing, you know, how
much I sent for an episode.
It helps you get confirmation
that the software's
working and that everything's working.
It also makes me feel good, you know,
and it also helps me, like, you know,
I need to give these guys some more.
Yeah, I've done that, too.
I've gone back and
looked and thought I had
boosted more on a certain show than I did.
And I'll go back and, you
know, top it off or whatever.
You know, that's also the tricky stuff.
Because one thing is, you know, to earn
more sets by being boosted by others.
And that's great.
Then you have revenue.
But the thing is, you know,
you're probably going to
be addicted to podcasts
as well and to boosting podcasts as well.
So, you know, making sure that your
expenses is actually not too much.
Oh, no, it's important.
Oh, yeah.
This job has cost me more than
any other job in my life.
You see?
For sure.
Oh, yeah, for sure.
But we're also circular, which is exactly
how network effects begin and grow.
You know, you got Dreb Scott.
You know, he's self, you know,
boosting himself indirectly.
And he gets it and sends it back and,
you know, goes to all other podcasts.
And I see Oscar from Fountain and
he's testing his boost on podcasts.
It's the whole system is so obvious
that it's working and it's growing.
And, you know, we're
just trying to, I guess,
in a way to keep up with the excitement and
get the tools out and get stuff working
or working better because it's there.
This flywheel, it's a
perpetual motion machine.
It's not stopping.
It does not stop.
The beauty of starfish organizations.
Starfish.
Let's see.
Oh, like a, yeah, like a hub and spoke.
No, you know, there's this great
book, The Starfish and the Spider,
that differentiates centralized
and decentralized systems.
By the spider, you cut off its head and
it's dead, even though it has eight legs.
But a starfish, if you cut it
in half, instead of it dying,
the two halves grow separately and
become two different starfish.
Oh, so it's like the, like the,
like the bad guy on Hellboy.
You kill, you kill one of
them and two are born.
Two are born.
Yes, exactly.
Or like the octopus.
You know, you always want the octopus.
Do you ever see that movie, the
documentary about the octopus?
That thing was crazy.
I love that, man.
You can eat your octopus, buddy,
and it'll grow a new leg, new food.
I have, I have not had calamari
since I saw that documentary.
That thing, that thing was legit.
Yeah.
I think it was a legit person.
You've seen it, Max?
You know, I wonder what would happen
if you give an octopus a full note?
Would he get it?
I think, I think an octopus is
definitely has intelligence.
And if he had the input, if you could
feel the inputs and the outputs, maybe.
Have you seen that documentary,
Max, what we're talking about?
Yeah.
The life of the octopus.
No, my octopus.
My octopus life.
Wasn't that right?
My octopus teacher.
Teacher.
Yeah.
That's teacher.
Amazing.
Okay.
Back on track.
Sir Bill, he sends a message for 950
sats and he just says, testing emojis,
decode this message.
Okay.
So, I put the emoji in there
if you want to open it up.
It's a...
Oh, hold on a second.
I think I saw this because the
emojis came through for me.
They did not come through for
me and it may just be my...
Oh, really?
How about maybe your mail client?
Because I thought...
Yeah.
Let me see.
Where is it?
Where is the...
Boostergram decodethemessage.png.
Oh, hold on.
Boostergram.
I'm on Fastmail, so it's
got this webmail client.
Is it LeBoost emoji?
Oh, no.
Decode the message.
Okay.
Yeah.
Decode the message.
That's...
Yeah, I saw that, but I didn't get it.
It was like guy, toilet,
rocket ship, megaphone.
Okay, so his follow-up is...
You can't decode it?
Oh, doctor.
Wait, I see it.
It's a doctor, toilet,
rocket ship, megaphone.
Obviously, while you're sitting in the
spaceship to the moon on the toilet,
you've got to blast the latest Bitcoin
and podcasting propaganda to everyone.
Okay, Max.
All right.
Well done, sir.
Well done.
No, no, no.
No, that's wrong.
He gives the answer in another
follow-up Boostergram.
Oh, oh, oh, okay.
He says the answer is Fauci Boost.
Oh.
Okay.
Fauci Boost.
Here we go.
Oops.
Wait.
Boost.
There you go.
Fauci Boost.
Goodness.
Does that qualify as an
abusive Boostergram?
Yeah.
How many sats was that?
950.
No, he didn't make it.
That's pretty low, though.
He skirted in right above the line.
Okay.
475 sats from Pitar.
P-E-T-A-R.
And his message, another one that I
couldn't decode, as far as the emojis,
but it just says,
Le Boost.
Let me see.
Oh, and he has a...
You guys have no idea what
beast you have released here.
Yeah, no, I kind of.
So he has a lion and a rocket ship.
No, that's a poodle.
Poodle?
Yeah.
Poodle, lion.
What's the difference?
Okay, yeah, if I zoom in.
Yeah, okay, so poodle,
well, it also has a period.
Poodle, period, boost.
French, a French boost.
It's a French poodle.
Yeah.
Le Boost.
Oh, okay.
I got it.
Wow.
You know, this is going too far.
It's okay.
The French want to take over
podcasting, but you can't...
I don't want that in my Booster Grams.
Le Booster Gram.
Open up the Booster...
There's another picture in there.
Oh, my God.
There's another...
Booster Gram on the SSH.
Because I couldn't read these on my email,
but I could read them in the SSH
console, which was hilarious.
Emojis on the Linux command line are
almost impossible to understand.
Okay, well, so there I have...
Yeah, I see the same ones.
Yeah.
But I give them kudos for trying.
It actually...
Wow, how does that work?
That's interesting.
I don't know.
I love command line, man.
Good work.
That's cool.
Well, Martin, I mean, Michael.
Michael, star of Podland, yes.
Star of Podland.
4,750 sats.
Welcome back.
Welcome back, Michael.
Finally getting to listen
to this week's episode.
Time to boost.
Ah, yes.
Boost.
Okay, there's a lot of these.
Oh, my God.
Okay, 50,000 sats from Auburn Citadel.
That sounds like a very
Bitcoin name to me.
Auburn Citadel, War Eagle.
Keep up the hard work.
Important for the future of free speech.
Boost.
Yes, boost.
Thank you.
50,000 sats.
This is great.
I love this.
It's crazy.
6,621 sats from Daniel N.
He says, I would like to
restate my previous message.
Adam, for the first time, you have
time to podcasting 2.0 perfectly.
Keep it up.
Yeah, I'm the curse of inventions.
It's like I'm always 10 years too early
and someone else becomes a billionaire.
And I'm a bit scared that the
same is happening right now.
Because, you know,
lightning, hey, it works.
I mean, great.
Damn, it's a hack.
And so I'm seriously not sure if you're
actually not going to break the whole
network with too much throughput.
Yeah, well, I mean, the only time I got
people's attention in the lightning world is
when I say, yeah, we're doing
70,000 transactions a month.
Like, what?
What?
Well, I posted on the Balance of Satoshi's
Telegram channel the other day because
the BOS command line
tool just kept crashing.
When I tried to pull an accounting
report, it was right out of memory.
Yeah, the memory on the node dies.
Were you trying to do a
month report or a year?
I was doing a month.
Oh, yeah.
I won't even handle that.
We had 328,000 transactions
at that time on our node.
Yeah.
And I asked him, I said, is there,
I asked Alex Bosworth, I was like,
is there a magic limit here that
things start to fall apart?
He said, no, he said it,
he said it should be fine.
Did you tell him how many
transactions we were doing?
Yeah, he didn't, he
didn't seem to phase him.
But yeah, like, yeah,
like Max said, I mean,
there is a number and
we're going to find it.
Yeah.
Oh, yeah.
No, we will find, we will
find the limits for sure.
And when we find it,
I'll let everybody know.
Jeff gave us 4,040 sats and he
says, that is Dreb's real face.
He says, my best friend's sister's boyfriend's
brother's girlfriend heard from this
guy who knows this kid
who's going with a girl
who saw Dreb's face at
31 Flavors last night.
I believe it.
Dreb, you are an ugly man.
Chad Farrow, the forever
promo cheerleader for us.
Chad Farrow gave us 50,000 sats
and says, Chad, thanks, man.
Celebrating show number 50.
Now everyone hug and share a secret.
Yes.
Man, he even, you know,
he sent the boost in advance
knowing when the publishing
time was for the new one
or the recording time.
Man, genius, genius.
This concept is too good, man.
I think we're breaking the matrix.
Mad skills.
Mad skills, Mac.
And the last boostagram is from Oscar
Mary, the developer of Fountain.
Fountain, yeah.
550 sats.
And his message just
says, can you hear me?
Yes.
We can hear you.
We got you.
Thank you very much.
It works.
It worked.
Speaking of hearing, actually, how about
that the boostagrams contain an MP3 file?
Oh, that's, see, it's too clever by
half because you're going to, that's,
it's like sending pictures.
You're going to, because every time
you get one of those, you're going to,
you're going to hover with
your mouse over the top.
And like, do I really
want to click this thing?
You know, I, I, years ago,
I decided to limit the attachment size
for my email server to 10 megabytes.
Good call.
So, people will send
you the craziest stuff.
I mean, how many .iso files I've
seen come in over the years?
I don't know.
It's like, come on, man.
An ISO.
Yeah.
Here's a Linux distro, man.
No, it's usually like,
hey, here's a, you know,
here's the Windows installed
disk you were looking for.
No, no.
So, Max, the Wasabikas podcast,
y'all are getting sats, right?
Yes, very much.
Hooked up to my, to my own note.
But, you know, even back then on
the World Crypto Network, you know,
I was the guy showing a Bitcoin on-chain
address in a QR code, you know, and,
and, and hoping people toss
me an on-chain transaction.
And, you know, I've, and another
fun thing, you know, we've,
this friend of mine also co-host at
the World Crypto Network, ARKBTC,
he's built these awesome
Internet of Things devices
connected to his Bitcoin full node, right?
So, for example, whenever, so there's
a QR code on the live stream, right?
Whenever someone pays sats to that QR
code above a certain threshold, you know,
a boxing glove machine punched
him in the face, you know,
or a smoke machine goes off right
into his mouth, you know, like weird,
fun things that you can do with
Bitcoin Lightning payments, man.
It's, it's crazy.
Are you going to do, no,
you got a full node.
I mean, you're going to do booster grams.
You got to, you got to start
pulling the booster grams out.
Yeah, man, how do I do that, actually?
It's the TLV, it's the 762.169, I
think, whatever that, that TLV,
it's got the payload in it.
Offhand.
It's got the payload in it, and it's,
it's all documented on the
Satoshi's.stream GitHub repo.
How do you, how do you decode that, Dave?
What, what magic sauce
do you use for that?
It's just, well, it's,
it's just hex encoded.
And so it's a, it's a type
length variable encoding.
Oh, yes, I did that just last night.
So is there like a command line interface?
I'm sure there is.
You can decode it with the, was it XXR
or command on, it's in most distros.
I think it's called XXR.
And you can, you can decode
it with that, but I'm using,
I'm in PHP most of the time.
So I'm using a bin to hex, but
any of those things will do it.
Yeah.
You just, you just decode it.
And then it's J, it decodes to JSON.
And then you just extract all
the properties out of it.
Yes.
It's dead simple.
Yeah.
Sounds like it.
The monthly, our monthly guys.
Oh my goodness.
But wait, there's more.
Podverse.
Give us $50.
Oh, that's Martin.
These are the subscriptions.
No, I'm not mine.
It's Mitch.
Mitch.
Sorry.
There's so many pods.
Be a bit more creative if
your names guys come on.
Oh, well, I can't blame them.
Mike Newman, $10.66.
He's $0.66.
He's the keeper of the team
repo that documents everybody.
Yeah.
Yes.
Really important.
Appreciate it.
Yeah.
Really great.
Lauren Ball, $24.20.
He's a longtime supporter of us.
Mitch Downey coming in again with $10.
Chris Sharabarak.
Every single time.
I'm going to miss that thing.
$10.
He sends it in just to
hear you mess it up.
I think so.
Chris Cowan, $5.
Jeremy Kavanaugh, $10.
Jeffrey Rutherford, $5.
Paul Saltzman, $22.22.
Damon Kasajak, $15.
David Norman, $25.
Miss you, David.
Yeah, we miss you, man.
And Søren Mohler, $10.
That's everybody.
That's our group.
Wow.
Thank you all so much for,
yeah, for supporting us.
You're with your treasure, certainly
here as Witness, your boosts.
Some of you monthly guys,
too, like check your balance.
I mean, check how much you've
donated because you made,
I'm sure you got a T-shirt coming.
Yeah, a T-shirt should be
there for you, for sure.
And if you want to convert some of
your Bitcoin into fiat fun coupons,
I'll get it eventually.
Then just go to podcastindex.org,
scroll down to the bottom.
There's a big red donate button.
There's also this, as pointed out
earlier, there's a Sphinx chat.
We should probably replace that
with a lightning something,
make it a little bit easier.
And thank you all very much
for supporting Podcasting 2.0,
the Podcasting 2.0 podcast,
the boardroom, podcastindex.social, all
the servers, and keeping the note funded.
I mean, with all these Boostergrams,
we can probably afford to put like some
crown molding up here in the boardroom.
Hey, I don't care about that.
I'd do this from a trailer if we had to.
We're not far from it, but
still, we're not quite there.
I'm all starry-eyed now.
Hey, Max, man, really appreciate you
being in the boardroom this week.
That was really interesting.
I think even for people who
just have a marginal interest,
I think that you could
learn a lot from it.
I really appreciate your explanation.
No, thanks a bunch for getting me on here.
It's really been a pleasure of
just listening to you guys.
And I've learned so much, you know,
and it's oftentimes just that you
provide a new spin on an old idea,
but that new way of looking at things just
blows my head so much that I'm sitting
there half broken for a couple
hours until I recompose myself.
Wow.
But it's, you know, it's awesome
to, like, it's so crazy.
Like, I've, one of the first videos
I've watched about Bitcoin was Andreas
Antonopoulos talking about
streaming money, you know,
in between autonomous driving vehicles
so that if you want to overtake,
one car pays the other
car a couple of cents.
Sure, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, I get that.
And, you know, like, this was,
like, 2015 or 16, like, you know,
even before Lightning was out there.
And nowadays, man, I look at my wallet
and I just see every day transactions are
coming in and I get more cents every day.
I spend way more cents than I earn,
obviously, but, you know, it's, it's, man,
that this magic works, it really
makes me speechless, man.
This is such a big win for freedom.
I love it.
I mean, we didn't even,
we're going to have to have you back
home because we didn't even talk.
I mean, I have, like, five questions here
on my little notepad about Wasabi wallet.
And I've got a big thing here from the Mises
Institute about inflation that I wanted
to talk to you about.
Like, there's, like, I mean, we could
talk for, like, two more hours easily.
So, yeah, we got to get you back.
Like, the conversation starts
three hours in, right?
Absolutely.
That is true.
Where should people go to find out
more about what you're doing, Max?
Is that for the WasabiWallet.io
or do you have other places,
the launching place they can find more?
Yeah, WasabiWallet.io is for
sure a place to check out,
especially in the next couple months
because we're releasing Wasabi 2.0.
I guess where you got that name from.
Do tell.
And it's really a complete
rewriting of the wallet.
We've learned so much over the
last couple years building it.
And this is our effort
to make it even better.
And it's huge.
It's been a monumental work.
And I'm so proud that it is so
close before release in two weeks.
Well, yeah, definitely.
And when you come back, I want to
ask you some stuff about CoinJoin.
And, you know, you're a wonderful
resource to be able to tap into.
And Wabi Sabi and all
that stuff you're doing.
Exactly.
That's all part of that.
And I mean, you know, for
the podcasting 2.0 crew,
since you're so lightning
focused, you might not even...
CoinJoin is not as big of a deal than
for other users who are on the Bitcoin
blockchain all the time.
Even though you can do cool CoinJoin
magic when opening and closing a channel,
ultimately, hopefully, this will
all be magic under the hood.
But, you know, this is
definitely a very advanced
and really powerful Bitcoin wallet.
So check it out.
And, yeah, my personal website
is towardsliberty.com.
That's where I share a bunch of knowledge
about Bitcoin, mainly economics.
Yeah, you got courses there, right?
You can sign up for a course.
Yes, exactly.
And here, you know, I kind of have a
confession to make that here I'm still hanging
on to the old principle
of a paywall, basically.
And, man, it's not working for all
the reasons that we both know.
So the only thing, really,
that's holding me back from a full value-to-value
model is that there's no nice chat
and video application that has the smooth
UI and UX integration that podcasts now
have for streaming Sats from anyone
in the call to anyone in the call.
And I have, like, two feature requests
open in both BTC Pay and Ellen Bits.
I think 20 million Sats bounty,
so if anyone out there is willing to write
a BTC Pay plugin that makes that possible
somehow with Jitsi or something, I
will pay you happily because this is,
that is almost as big as
podcasting 2.0 streaming
is to stream Sats during
a live conversation.
That'd be great, yeah.
Wow, okay.
Yeah, why not?
Yeah, hopefully when we get
to the point of doing live,
doing the live tag and all that stuff.
Some of that will work.
Yeah, some of that will fix itself, yeah.
Because that's what we
planned for this show, too.
I mean, as soon as we get
the live stuff working,
we're going to start going
live and doing it that way.
And on the video front, I just wanted to
mention, because I have it on my list,
that Rumble is now the Rumble video site.
They're really taking an initiative here.
They're funded.
They are advertising-based.
They are now positioning themselves
as an alternative to YouTube,
and they just hired, or
that's not fair to say,
they did a deal with Glenn
Greenwald, who, of course,
is already, I think he
has a sub-stack deal.
I know he, I subscribe to his stuff there.
But I think they also pay him additional.
They do that with a lot of writers.
That by itself is, they don't, there's not
even a competitor, really, to sub-stack.
So, Rumble is making an incredible
play, but when you look down into it,
you're going to be just as deplatformable
from Rumble as anywhere else.
And I think there's an incredible opportunity
on the way as people are now accepting
alternatives for No Agenda
Tube and, you know,
the Peer Tube-type infrastructure
that we're hooking
up for that to really get a foothold.
Oh, yeah.
That'd be great.
Yeah, I'm really excited about that.
Bitcoin is unfuckwithable
magical internet money,
and podcasting is unfuckwithable
broadcasting of speech.
The two go so well together, and the
two guys put them together is awesome.
Another two T-shirts.
It is literally two
sides of the same coin.
Value going one way, value
coming the back the other way.
That's so much it.
All right.
You want to throw an ISO in there?
Information war?
Sure I do.
We are in an information war.
And what's the, is this the end of
show Rulfi mix we played last time?
Yeah, it's, no, it's not from
last, it's from way back.
And this is from like, oh
gosh, almost a year ago.
Yeah.
Yeah, we played it once.
Once like eight months ago.
Okay.
No, no, no.
You know, we're long today, man.
Okay.
This is the longest show we've ever done.
Oh, is it?
Yeah.
Oh, yeah.
No, we're like 214.
We're out of control.
Max, thank you so much, man.
Have a great weekend.
Dave, have yourself a great weekend.
Everybody in the boardroom, take care.
See you on the next one.
Bye-bye.
See you guys.
All right.
And we'll be back next Friday with
another meeting of the board here,
Podcasting 2.0.
See you then.
Bye-bye.
You're listening to Podcasting 2.0.
Visit podcastindex.org
for more information.
Boost!
Bombshell.
Go podcasting!